<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jing's Corner</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/</id><updated>2013-10-19T21:33:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>From Wordpress to Github</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/From%20Wordpress%20to%20Github.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-19T21:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-10-19:From Wordpress to Github.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As it says in the title, today is the grand opening of my new website. All the posts from
Wordpress which I wrote in the past have been moved. From now to the end of this year, I
will continue improving the sites. So if you have any suggestion, please let me know. At
the moment, there are still some bugs. Hopefully they will get fixed after I learn better
how Pelican, css and HTML work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this new site, I hope that I can write more frequently. I know I have said the same
thing many times before, but hopefully this time, it will become true.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Alpe d'Huez, here I come</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/alpe-dhuez-here-i-come.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-22T22:51:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-04-22:alpe-dhuez-here-i-come.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First time I heard of this mountain peak&amp;nbsp;was when one of my
ex-colleagues at Philips asked me to sponsor him for cycling up Alpe
d'Huez to raise money for one of the cancer foundations. Alpe&amp;nbsp;d'Huez is
also part of Tour de France.&amp;nbsp;Then I thought maybe one day I would give
it a try. When chances came, I was just ready to go. Last weekend, a
couple of &amp;nbsp;friends were driving down to Grenoble&amp;nbsp;with one of the plans
being cycling up Alpe d'Huez. It was first time for all of us. We had no
idea how difficult it would be but we kind of knowing it for sure, one
way or another, we would make it to the top. The beginning of the
climbing was difficult, but once I got the rhythm&amp;nbsp;of it, it became
easier and easier and after a little while, I could just continue riding
the bike and left all the guys behind me. Theory proves less weight
helps. As a team, I waited and took the break with the guys and after
some persistence, we all happily made it to the top after cycling 14km
straight up, at the altitude of 1850m. After you made it, it seemed it
was not all that difficult after all. Of course, then you make new
goals. The people who join the fund raising event in summer normally
cycle up and down for 6 times on one day. For that, not just some luck
and try, one will really need to train hard for it. All in all, it was a
nice try. Photos can be seen &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://s1071.photobucket.com/user/jingjingzou/library/Place/Grenoble?sort=3&amp;amp;page=1"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Thoughts out of a random question over income</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/thoughts-out-of-a-random-question-over-income.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-06T11:52:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-04-06:thoughts-out-of-a-random-question-over-income.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I asked Ralf: How long can I live on the savings if I do not
have a job from tomorrow? I had a year or two at most in mind. But Ralf
answered, probably until the rest of your life, if you consider a large
part of this world's population lives on 2 dollar or less per day.
&amp;nbsp;Indeed, if a person earns 2 dollar a day and work 360 days per year,
for a working life of 40 years, the total earning is 28,800 dollars. This is not an
assumption but a sheer fact, referring to&amp;nbsp;some figures from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_inequality"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wealth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;over 80% of the world population lives on less than 10 US$/day.;&amp;nbsp;over
50% of the world population lives on less than 2 US$/day;&amp;nbsp;over 20% of
the world population lives on less than 1.25 US$/day;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in the Netherlands or any other western developed country or most
parts of China nowadays even, it is almost unimaginable to live under 2
US$/day. The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gemiddeld-inkomen.nl/"&gt;average Dutch income&lt;/a&gt; in 2012 is&amp;nbsp;€ 33.000.&amp;nbsp;While I asked
the question, my immediate assumption was on maintaining my current
living standard, meaning living in a confortable house with heating,
going out once in a while, flying to China once a year or to other
places for holidays etc. It is easy to take all these luxuries for
granted just because everybody around me here has the similar living
standard, and I work hard to deserve it. I guess the truth is that we do
not on average work harder than the people who earn 2US$/day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is some food for thought. The world as it is today, faces a lot of
challenges ahead. Let us not leave these challenges only to the people
who are directly concerned or only to celebrities. You or me or anybody
else can be part of the solution to these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>500m breaststroke is no problem</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/500m-breaststroke-is-no-problem.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-01T20:37:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-04-01:500m-breaststroke-is-no-problem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I went swimming. For the first time, I have swam for 500m without
a pause. I have no idea since when I could actually do this. Before I
have just never tried it. You will never believe you can do it until you
actually start doing it. So that is my learning for today. Surprising
yourself, that is what you have to do from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW, I started working out also, push ups, stretches, jump rope and some
other exercises which I can not even name them. From now on, I just need
to keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Sometimes you just feel like writing something down</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/sometimes-you-just-feel-like-writing-something-down.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-31T19:46:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-03-31:sometimes-you-just-feel-like-writing-something-down.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been a long time that I actually start writing something down. It
did occur to me a few times before that I wanted to write something down
to reflect upon what I had been doing, but it did not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So actually I am pretty happy to find out my wordpress account still
works, which offers means when I do want to record something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often say to people 'that is really cool and I want to do it too
someday'. I have a lot of 'wants'. Sometimes I will just have to
translate the 'want' into actions, then it actually can become true.
Looking at my progress of keeping up the goals I set this year for
myself over the first quarter, I would say I have had a slow start so
far. The good thing is that I shall still look forward. With the weather
getting better and the day getting longer, I will have much more passion
to do more sports outside. So it is not yet too late to catch up. Easier
said than done, I will just have to check up on myself once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you all later.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Forwarded: My Farewell Letter</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/forwarded-my-farewell-letter.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-28T16:55:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2011-06-28:forwarded-my-farewell-letter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Actually I did write something. Below is my farewell letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Fortimo is one of Philips brand for LED lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HELLOOOO AND GOODBYE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, there,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many of you have already known, today is my last day &amp;#64; Shanghai
office. Very complicated feelings often occur to me at such moments.
Therefore, I have recorded below a short conversation I had with Ms
Fortimoie Shanghai (first name: Fortimoie) when I was still calm and
sober.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: So why do you leave me?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: please allow me to apologize first of all. It was not my
intention to leave you but I had to make this decision because my
laogong relocated to the Netherlands.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: I see, that makes me feel slightly better. I thought you do
not like me:(.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: That is absolutely not the case. I do enjoy working with you, it
is such a dynamic environment and it is full of passion and challenges.
Also, you have so many fans around the whole Asia pacific region. It is
really a great pleasure to have been working here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: I am happy you enjoyed it. What are you going to do&amp;nbsp; next?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: Guess what, I am going to work for one of your relatives, who is
also one of your fans but located at 120degs across the globe. His name
is OEM EMEA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: Oh, that is nice, I am glad you are still in the same world
as me then. Do you think you will come back in the future?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: Yeah, I would definitely like to in the future when there is a
good opportunity. So please do not forget about me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: That is good. But… but it is kind of sad still.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: Ah, don’t be sad. Let me tell you a joke: ‘there's a family of
tomatoes walking down the street: the daddy tomato, the mommy tomato and
the baby tomato. The daddy tomato is becoming more and more annoyed with
the baby tomato because the baby tomato is taking its time dragging his
feet looking at everything. so finally the daddy tomato turns around and
walks back to where the baby tomato is &amp;amp; steps &amp;amp; smuches the baby tomato
&amp;amp; screams: &amp;quot;Ketchup!&amp;quot;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: hahaha, fine, you can turn off your laptop and get ready to
leave, take care … :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day. Wish you all the best all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jing&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I am back to Holland</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/i-am-back-to-holland.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-28T16:48:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2011-06-28:i-am-back-to-holland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been such a long time that I ever wrote anything. When I read the
last post on this blog,&amp;nbsp; I was questioning myself whether I am the
person who wrote that. But I had excuses since Wordpress, Facebook,
Twitter are all blocked in China. Now it is the chance, since I just
moved back to China after about 1.5 years living in Shanghai. I am
excited in a way because I consider it is a start of a new life again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday, Ralf and I went hiking around Drie Land Pont and we
happened to be at the highest point of the Netherlands: 327.5m. I was
quite excited by the fact that it is highEST. The important matter of
fact here is that I am generally impressed by first or est, such as
most, best, tallest, fastest and so on. Then I told Ralf, how about we
have an EST day every week. Once we run out of good ideas of being
..est, we can just eat most hamburgers for example. While I am writing
this down, trust me that I am really getting excited about this idea :)
If this comes true, I will never have a problem in finding materials for
blogging anymore. Whoever reads this can of course contribute to my EST
idea. I will just try it out at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW: we learnt at the highest point of the Netherlands: the Dire land
pont was once upon a time Fier Land Pont. The 4th land was Sc.., which
then became part of Belgium. I got to learn better the history of the
Netherlands and the neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome myself to the Netherlands again!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Job-Life</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/job-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-27T00:08:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2009-03-27:job-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is rather not an easy topic for the moment. Every single day in the
past months, it appeared in the news that thousands people get laid off.
Though I am not panic about myself, but such news rather made me at
unease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking a lot about what Steve Jobs spoke in the speech
given to Stanford 'As with all matters of the heart, you'll know when
you find it, and like any great relationship it just gets better and
better as the years roll on. So keep looking. Don't settle.' Job
occupies the biggest portion of life since I usually disregard sleeping
as a part unless I found some solutions or came across some joyful
events in my dream, which is rather rare for me anyway. I am no way near
settled with my job but on the other hand, I have not really kept
looking. Where do I exactly stand and where should I head to, I do not
have a clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do people see their jobs? It is hard to judge one by one. However,
there are several possibilities. Some people hate their job, it is
deemed that life is much less pleasant than it should be until one day
the limit is reached and they quit; some people step out of it, they may
enjoy their work, may not, but they make themselves aware that work is
just part of the deal of life. So they do their job and move on with
life, which apparently contradicts with what Steve said. I would not
consider this wrong since not everyone is as lucky that they know what
exactly they are fascinated with. I certainly donot know what would be
my ideal job for life. Then comes the lucky ones, they love their jobs
and they are excited about their work. I do not know what more to
comment but to admire such gurus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mainland China and many other developing countries, it is safe to
say, many people work for life. No work, no sustainable life at all.
Though I am like quite like that, but I donot think I am completely
immune from the thought of work for life. People have to work to survive
in whichever case, but some people can choose what work to do, while
some donot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still searching where I am. Maybe I could adopt some thought or
attitude of others to make job both easy and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>another year - 1st post of 2009</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/another-year-1st-post-of-2009.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-01-17T13:53:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2009-01-17:another-year-1st-post-of-2009.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am now sitting in a Starbucks, waiting for the movie 'Australia' to be
screened within a couple of hours on the top floor of this department
store. In fact, I have been here for most of the afternoon reading. The
weather was good and enough sunshine to keep me warm sitting outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year 2008 is gone and immediately followed by year 2009. Meanwhile so
many years have past in the history of human beings. All what I could
possibly know about the past relies in the books, or occasionally
historical films and the rest I have to depend on my own imagination.
People have to always look forward since the past can not be changed but
somehow luckily you still have a little control over your future.
Nevertheless, the past brought you experience and we can all learn about
our past and hopefully wisdom will be built up with the appearance of
the wrinkles at the corner of your deepening eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking into my past, it has been smooth and almost frustration free
apart from occasional modern man-made fuss, which is not worth to
mention. 4 years in university followed by 4 years in UK plus one year
with a job, 9 years of life has past but I obtained a lot (hopefully)
from the life and have got what is left all stays in my mind. However,
these many years, I still have not been able to follow the fashion of
the modern society. I still do not care what I am not used to care, such
as dresses, skin protection, all kinds of beauty treatment, fashion and
so on. I am looking around me now, the girls with shopping bags are in
mini-skirt, high heels, curly hair, nicely curved eye-brow ... I start
wondering why I am not like that. Is there anything missing in my life
or I cling to my past no matter what, or I still indulge myself stupidly
just to mark myself different from others. Fortunately it is never good
to judge your own life based on other peoples' standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to my last year, I have been without a home since mid Feb
and ever since I stayed most of the 365 days in a hotel room. How do I
feel? I think it is all right since I chose the job and I wanted to try
what I and most of other people have not tried. But am I really enjoying
it? It is lonely and you end up with a lot of time which you have to
fill it in all by yourself. Nevertheless, I have seen a bit of different
parts of the world so far and most importantly, I have entered the unit
of the society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, I have completely forgotten what I originally wanted to write in
this post. Well, whatever, I have to go for my movie now.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Caption of album items</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/caption-of-album-items.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-21T12:08:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-12-21:caption-of-album-items.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have added some captions to the photos in my photo album. Some stories
are told that way. So please do not miss out :) I remember Olga once
asked about it, so in the future I will try my best to release the
photos with captions. Then I will definately select my photos more
carefully to upload each time, since after one weekend trip, definately
more than 400 photos. Well, it is free afterall;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>It is almost another year</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/it-is-almost-another-year.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-20T17:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-12-20:it-is-almost-another-year.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year almost comes to an end and I start wondering what is going to
be my new year's resolution. For the last few years, I always tried to
have one but whether it really worked has never been&amp;nbsp; checked. However,
now I think about it but I already forgot what was my last year's
resolution. I kind of know what I wish but just not sure how to make it
happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is kind of hard to summarize what I have done for this whole year but
I will categorize my activities into the following: the things I had to
do, the things I wanted to do and the things I wanted to do but not yet
done. So now, the things I had to do, such as eating, cleaning, going to
work, sleeping and you name it; since you have to do them, so it seems
rather important but on the other hand can be much less fun. The things
I wanted to do, such as doing my job seriously, keeping this blog,
learning swimming, being conscious what is going on in this world and of
course the most important thing both Ralf and I wanted: becoming really
family. Though the life after marriage has not really changed yet, but
we are the family and we know we will hold on together no matter what
difficulties we are going to encounter. As for the things I wanted to do
but not yet done, I am afraid the list can go on forever. But I will
name a few which are on top of my head since they are of importance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First one, I should have better control when I am down. It is hard to
admit but I do think I am a little self-centered, since once I am
unhappy or distressed, my thought can be so negative which may impact
others. Since I mention this, I will take the opportunity to apologize
to Ralf because he suffered most when I was down. It is always
afterwards I regret I should have better control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is that to help the poor better. I do not really know how
to address this issue since my capability is small though I wish so much
I can make a change. I am easily touched but also easily forget. When I
am touched, resentment is meanwhile produced, why life has to be so
unfair and why the gap is getting larger all the time. It is a really
meaningless complaint, since sxxt happens all the time at some parts of
the world. However, little effort is better than nothing and I will bear
this in mind, hope you do as well, dear readers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is for sure now another day, so nothing left but sleepiness :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Howard hotel, Hsinchu.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Spot the difference</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/spot-the-difference.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-17T16:01:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-12-17:spot-the-difference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is most different between mainland China and Taiwan?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was asked this question almost on any occasion of a conversation.
Honestly I do not really know whether I am actually in a position of
telling something genuine and interesting since the time of my stay is
still too short to form an opinion, also my contact with Taiwanese is
really limited to certain groups such as colleagues at work, crews at
the hotel and the taxi drivers. However, I would always like to give it
a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing which comes into my mind is in following Chinese
traditions. Somehow, from what I have heard and read, Taiwanese seem to
be more traditional in a way even though they are developed and open
much earlier than mainland China. The most convenient example is the
usage of traditional Chinese characters and the format of books in
Taiwan. Some books are still written vertically from the right to the
left. I have to admit that I lost interest and desire to read a book
like that, since it is simply going to take me too much effort even
though I may have a chance to understand well the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then the wedding. I heard it most since 4 colleagues got married one
after each other. Also, a few got engaged. There is usually an
engagement party, which is held by the girl normally but funded by her
fiance (bride price),&amp;nbsp; The party is of various sizes, ranged from 1
table to couples of dozens table. From the pictures I have seen, it is
just like a wedding but somehow smaller than the real wedding. The bride
also changes dresses through the course of the party and they were made
fun of at the mean time. For many young people in China nowadays, this
step is skipped I think (at least most of my friends do not have an
engagement party). The party itself maybe similar afterall, since
afterall, it is with tons of people and a lot of food. But there is one
thing which I have never seen before is that how they decorate the car
which is used to pick up the bride. I have seen two versions so far
(every weekend, there are wedding or engagement parties in the hotel,
since it is said in the Chinese calendar these days are good days): two
sugarcanes or two banboos with roots and a buddle of pork are tied to
the right side on the top of the car. Not sure whether people in Fujian
or somewhere else in the South still do such things. See, Mainland is so
big and I have only visited a fraction of it so hard to say this is
indeed the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Street vendors. You will hardly see street vendors in big cities in
China anymore, but they are almost everywhere in Taiwan. Taiwan is
famous for its snacks and normally you can find in one city the snacks
from all other parts of Taiwan. It is sometimes sold at the side of the
road, sometimes in a shed in a market. Even though some of them do have
a shop front but most of them look a little shabby and old comparing to
the restaurants in mainland. I actually really enjoy the food in such
restaurants since it is delicious, fast and convenient and also very
cheap. Most importantly, you do not have a chance to waste so much since
the portion is just about right at least for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Belief or religion. I do not have to say much about this but you may
have already known what is the outcome of this comparison. In mainland,
there are historical reasons why religion is not very popular since
communist party was in control. Even nowadays, the policy for religion
or belief is still like the wind, which can go either way from time to
time. In Taiwan, most of people believe in Buddhism or Daoism. There are
temples almost everywhere you go. As far as I know, there are 3 major
kinds: Buddist, Dao and Mazu temple. These temples have different gods,
which will offer differing protections. For example, in Tainan, almost
every village has Mazu temple. I was told, originally Mazu was from
Fujian province and her real name is Lin Moliang. She is very kind and
always trying to save fisherman's life when the sea is tough. In Tainan,
there were many fishermen in odl days, especially along the coast. They
built temples to respect Mazu and wish for a safe also productive
fishing trip. Most people go to temples to worship regularly once or
twice a month besides festivals. The general Principal of belief is
'rather believe in it than not' just in case it might be real. My
impression is that this belief is much more spread here than in Mainland
China since people even communicate about their worship experience at
lunch break. What a surprise for me! I kind of feel that I miss
something, since I do not have a belief or faith meanwhile a little
guilty that I am not as Chinese as them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last thing is not worth to mention but just for the sake of it:
People in Mainland (called Chinese with no doubt) consider Taiwan is
part of China, while most Taiwanese consider China is a foreign country
now. During A bian's time, Taiwanese learn Chinese history as foreign
history. Nevertheless, majority people in the north of Taiwan still
reckon they are Chinese since their ancestors were from Fujian province
in 16th century, while majority people in the South may consider they
are not even Chinese, Well, they both have a point, since during Dutch
38 years in Taiwan (40000 people and 40000 deer happily lived on this
island at the time), the encouraged immigrates from Fujian were mostly
men, later on who had to marry the aboriginal people who resided in
Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, I feel Taiwan is much more balanced between tradition and
modernity while in China some tradition is lost in a pursuit for
modernity. I wish one day we will become one country, one people again
due to our same root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Jing’s family</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/jings-family-migrated-from-the-wedding-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-20T15:16:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-11-20:jings-family-migrated-from-the-wedding-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;My parents have been living in Ningguo for all their life so far and they&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;intend to stay in Ningguo for the rest of their life. I moved out of&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;home when I started university in Shanghai in the year of 1999 and my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;sister entered university in 2005.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We have moved 6 times within Ningguo. From a big house in Red Star&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;village to a tiny semi-attached house in Feng Xing village, where the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;steel ball factory my father worked relocated. It is a house but&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;actually it only has one kitchen and one living room downstairs, and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;one bedroom with two beds and a 14-inch colour TV upstairs. I did not&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;recall any bad memories for staying in this little containment, except&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;for my sister being kicked out of the bed a few times during the three&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;years we stayed there. I still vividly remember there were 8 households&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;in a row and my house was the first in the row. The neighbours are&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;still very good friends of my family, especially the kids of my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;sister’s age.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The living area of the factory was divided into different parts and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;each part has one unique type of accommodation, such as the tiny little&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;double-floor house (step 1), two-bedroom bungalow (step 2), two-bedroom&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;apartment (step 3), three-bedroom apartment (step 4). The people who&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;worked in sales were generally better off in the factory so they may&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;jump in steps starting from step 3. It was like a ladder for my family,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;we experienced step 1 to step 3 and then we moved out of the factory&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;because my father started his own business in 1997. After step 3, we&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;went back to a similar step 1 again. Because my father quited his job,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;we had to move out immediately so we end up in a temporary match box&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;type compound again. It was simple, just two big rooms so we could be a&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;bit creative in how to make into a home for four. My parent’s bedroom&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;occupy one room, and the other we divided it into a kitchen and the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;bedroom for me and my sister. The advantage about this accommodation is&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;that it is in the city center and very close to my school but the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;disadvantage is that it is right below a dancing and Karaoke salon,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;which normally runs until 1am at earliest. I remembered by then a few&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;sleepless night for me and my sister. If we were lucky, sometimes a&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;nice song with a nice tune or close to the tune, but most of time ended&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;up with some shouting completely out of tune. However, I missed so much&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;the time when my sister and I went to the small restaurant after my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;school at night. We would always spend 5 yuan (50 cents) for a plate of&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;stir-fried sliced potato and two bows of plain rice or some spicy&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;noodles before we could go to sleep after the dancing salon stopped its&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;business.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Time flew as it is now. We moved to our new flat afterwards and my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;father’s business of steel ball mold seemed to move on the right track&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;and most importantly we did not have to suffer midnight shouting&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;anymore. My father always told us if he had not quited his job in that&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;factory, he would have never afforded me and my sister both going to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;universities. Of course he would not have afforded to built a house for&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;our family, nor any big purchase he made for the house. Also thanks to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;him, I was able to start my adventure in a foreign country via studying&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;in UK as my first stop. To be honest, I did not mean to break my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;promise to my father that I would go back home after my MSc study in&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Nano physics, but the study was so short that I simply did not have&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;enough of it so I stayed for my PhD with financial support from the UK&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;government and the university, which turned out to be the best choice&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;so far of my life otherwise this blog would not have existed at the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;first place.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I always believe in the butterfly effect, which means a small effect&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;can lead to a big event in the future. In this case, if Ralf had not&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;elbowed me in the conference hall when I spontaneously took the sit&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;next to him, he would not have asked for my hand under the statue at&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;the far end opposite the Windsor Castle.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;That is about it! But of course, I have lots of uncles and aunts and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;dozens of cousins and two grandmothers. Amazingly I feel very close to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;almost all of them. Guess it is because we all live close together,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;which means half an hour at most walking distance. Whenever I go home,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;there will be always big get-togethers all the time. One get-together&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;is never enough, because in China, who initiates the invitation will&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;pay for the dinner, so everyone wants to take turn to pay, so let us&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;start counting. My mother’s side has on total 6 siblings, same also at&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;my father’s side. so on total 12 dinners to go. This is not all, how&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;about my parents’ friends and our neighbours and my friends.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Invitations come in chains, one chain after another or chain twisted in&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;another chain, so everyday I or Ralf and I when we go back together,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;are booked from lunch to dinner if not breakfast! Since Ralf looks so&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;different from a normal Chinese, it made us even more popular! What a&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;phenomenon!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In China, the elders are mostly supported by their children because&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;there is almost no pension from the government unless the elder retires&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;from a job position within a government or from a government-own&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;factory. Both of my grandmothers have to depend on my parents and all&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;my uncles as well as my aunts. Fortunately my parents and their&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;siblings are not doing too bad, but for some elders, it can be a sever&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;problem. I have seen so many poor eldly people, so I always wanted to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;build an eldly home sometime in the future.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;So much about my family. They are all lovely people, I really hope you&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;will enjoy their company during the wedding.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Pieces</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/pieces.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-20T15:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-11-20:pieces.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;1. After all about Fengshui, please read this: All employees in A (maybe
many more) very big high tech company in taiwan (for confidentiality, no
name is offered here) , have to prey all together (sometimes department
by department to avoid tramped) to the father god of the earth (Tu Di
Gong 土地公) every month for prosperity of the company and also to keep
away the evil spirit. It is said there is even a legend person who is
believed to be the best at driving away evil spirit. Some high tech
company was so futunate to embrace her magic magic power to have fixed a
complex problem machine which is believed to be tangled with many small
ghosts for a long time. A Taiwaness colleague then commented seriously
what if we put a photo of Zheng Cheng Gong on our tool? (Zheng Cheng
Gong from Ming dynasty kicked the Dutch 'tradors' out of Taiwan in 17th
century). The overall attitude of people here: When you are not sure
whether it exists or not, you would rather believe in it
(宁可信其有，不可信其无) ----Very philosophical, isnot it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. A politician was seen very furious today on TV at lunch time. He was
shouting at somebody's face with his hand swirling in front of him
because Mr ex president of Taiwan A Bian has been granted with top class
prison treatment ' A Hot Shower'. He exploded since he did not receive
such top treatment when he served his time in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Politician's secret weapon: Protest with Fast plus forcible nutrition
injection. It is recorded that one of DDP members survived couple of
years during his sentence. Now Mr A Bian may have a chance to break this
record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Light stuff: The taxi driver says he normally enjoys his holiday
since he always goes abroad fishing. The rejoice of fishing lies in
taking a picture of the fish which has never seen then release them into
water again. If he has seen it before, then also not too bad, go to the
restaurant and have a nice fish meal as long as the fish meets the
fishable regulation of the country. In this aspect, he clains Japan is
better than Taiwan since the regulations in Japan on fishing is much
more relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More to continue when it happens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Taibei to Taipei</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/taibei-to-taipei.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-16T12:34:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-11-16:taibei-to-taipei.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the mainland China we use Taibei as its name. I do know really know
much about Taibei but still I am going to write down what I have seen
and felt since I only went there twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First time, I took the HSR (High speed rail) to Taipei just for the fun.
The HSR station is rather far out of Hsinchu, but nevertheless, it only
takes half hour to Taipei station from there. HSR runs&amp;nbsp; the north to the
south, which connects all the major cities on the western coast. I was
going to meet up with a colleague of mine who has been living in Taipei
for a while with her husband. However, we arranged to meet each other at
the HSR exit. Well, it was not such a good idea after all, since after I
got out of the train, I figured out there are 12 exits on total.
Nevertheless, we managed to find each other in the end with the help
from a friendly girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was pouring rain, so Katrin and I made a smart choice of staying
inside. I was eager to know how she feels in Taiwan. She loves it and
she admitted also as a foreigner here, she really feel privileged since
everyone seems to respect her and willing to help whenever it is needed.
I guess it is not totally unexpected since we have an old say, people
from outside are always guests. The stories I heard mostly about this
privilege is that they can always get away with some potential fines in
traffic since whenever the police stops them, he will have to let them
go since it is just too hard for the police to explain what is going
on.&amp;nbsp; One of the funny things she mentioned is, people always ask her
whether she is American. Somehow, she has the impression that Taiwaness
seem to consider the foreigners who are white or blond all Americans. We
do not really know why but we made two assumptions: too many americans
are living here, many of whom are English teachers; They just like
Americans since Americans helped them a lot in the beginning of the
founding of ROC. Nevertheless, speaking good English and look foreign
seems to be a big advantage in Taiwan. So one of my colleagues suggested
me to speak English instead of Chinese when I have to ask for some extra
service from the hotel. Well, it worked out well but I think the major
reason is that the poor girl who picked up the phone could not handle
English very well so she just said yes :) Well talking about this
privilege, I guess it is no good for me, since I have a distinct
mainland accent, which is easily recognized whenever I open my mouth.
Nevertheless, after I open my mouth with a few words, it is always
followed by a question: 'Are you from mainland?'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is so much about privilege. We visited a museum about the
aboriginals living in Taiwan, who now live mostly in the mountains and
on the eastern coast. They were the victims of every invasion from
outside world but now the government seems to attribute special
attention to them and help them to build up tourism to make a better
life. This reminds me that there are also 55 minority nations in China.
Somehow they must feel overwhelmed by the amount of Han people who
surrounded them and over the time, their life is gradually assimilated,
which is so called culture invasion. The special exhibition of this time
is about A Mei Zu. This tribe is led by female spiritual priests. To
become priest is not according to your will but the god's will (it is
not Jesue here!). If you are selected by the God, you will be sick and
nobody can cure you but the priests. Then you are one of them. Rather
spooky, well that is their traditions. My total impression is that all
those minorities are all good at dancing since they always dance at
festival time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last visit of the day was taipei 101, which beats the twin tower in
Malaysia and becomes number 1 highest in the world. The designer
admitted that he aims for number 1 since it always strikes the best
impression if it is #1 and why not. 101 is the fusion of Western modern
and traditional Chinese style. Western, because it is steel and glass
structures. Traditional because its bamboo structure and it has 8
sections and each section and it resembles a traditional Chinese square
'Dou' (money box), which is smaller at the bottom and bigger at the
opening. Each Dou has 8 floors and you all know why '8' not 7 or 9 :) At
each facade of the section, there are traditional Chinese symbols as
ornament: such as Ruyi, which connotes healing, protection and
fulfilment and is also a favorite decoration or imperialpalace.
Partially its interior looks like dragon's spines.&amp;nbsp; Another very Chinese
design is the Fengshui fountain in front of 101. After the engineers
finished all the designing job, Fengshui master comes in. He will make
the final touch or rather say final proof then the whole construction
can be started. There is a road which seems to cut through 101 if you
imagine if it is extended. This will drain off energy from the building
(bringing in negative energy), therefore the fountain is built to make
up with positive energy. How scientific, isnot it? Well, nevertheless,
it looks rather artistic and fits in well with the metal glass
structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story ends up with food. We had dinner at the food court at the
bottom floor of 101. I like Taiwanese xiao chi (small bites), but if you
are not careful, a lot of small bites can fill you up completely until
you feel difficult to walk. That happened to me a few times and I have
to exercise very hard in order to win some negative weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11月16日 于烟波酒店本馆&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Taiwan Sheng - Taipei Shi</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/taiwan-sheng-taipei-shi.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-10-31T17:11:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-10-31:taiwan-sheng-taipei-shi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First of all, I will have to explain what is 'sheng' and what is 'shi'.
'Sheng' means province and 'shi' means city. Private cars have two types
of registration zone: Taiwan Sheng and Taipei Shi, which means if a car
is registered anywhere outside Taipei in Taiwan , it will have 'Taiwan
Sheng' on its number plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do not judge my political view from this since I just found that
the above observation is a little bizarre and funny. To be honest, I
have been thinking for quite sometime, whether Taiwan is justified to be
a country from historical point of view. In my naive logic, the answer
will be 'Yes'. Simply speaking, Communist party knocked down the
government formed by Kuoming party then took the lead of the country
while Kuoming party fled to Taiwan after their defeat and ever since the
two parts went different ways and acted as two different countries. I
have no idea since when, China (People's Republic of China) started
officially claiming 'Taiwan is part of China' even though I do remember
I read in my textbooks that 'Taiwan is a province of China'. My naive
judgement is 'in history, the fight between two armies either resulted
in one big kingdom or two kingdoms with two kings or two emperors; in
our case, communist party did not really eliminate Kuoming party army so
it resulted in two kingdoms'. It is overly simplified politics and of
course does not at all represent the reality but hopefully some of you
would think it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do Chinese people (including people from both mainland and Taiwan)
really care? I think most of people do not care. Of course, if you do
ask a person from mainland 'Do you think Taiwan is independant', I guess
he or she will automatically gives you a default 'No' simply they get
used to the idea and also it is cool to have a great (large or vast)
country. Do Taiwanese care? I guess not too much, since they have just
elected a president who has openly stressed he would like to keep a good
tie with China even though there are a few people a little frightened
that the tie is going to be too close. Do I care? I think I only care to
an extend whether it is good for economics. For now, it is no good,
since strictly speaking still no direct flight since even the non-stop
weekend flight still has to make a detour above Hongkong and then head
back north to Taiwan, which takes around 4 hours from Shanghai or
Nanjing but instead, a real direct flight in space from Shanghai to
Taipei should be only one and half hours. Other disadvantages such as
'extreme difficulty for a Chinese to get a work permit in Taiwan and
vice Versa' and other restrictions in trading and communication.
Politics intends to cover the fact: we as Chinese all have same root
afterall and we are just same people. Why does politics (a game of few
people fighting for the power) create the chance for us to hate each
other and make enemies with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heard a nasty story about Mr A Bian, the former president. He can't
stand up in the North Taiwan now since people in the North (more
educated according to my taxi driver:)) are Kuoming pro; while he can
only talk in front of farmers from the South (I have not been to the
South, so tentatively borrowing the words from my taxi driver again).
What kind of person is he really? My first impression of judging people
is normally quite accurate, which consequently granted me a safe trip
home at a strange place with pizza delivery, and my impression of A Bian
is just ugly 'cunning, non trust-able, irresponsible ...'. The instant
proof is that he, his son with his blood and his daughter in law denied
their crime and the poor paralyzed lady, A Bian's wife and the son's
mum, became the easiest and most natural scapegoat. Well, have to say, A
Bian must have been a good husband since he was so obedient to his wife
that he dared to abuse his power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for today, my third night and second day in Taiwan. Biased
opinions can't be avoided since I have just been charged with communist
power for a month:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;于新竹烟波大酒店 都会一管 10/31 （25 days after being married to
Ralf-河马绕富）&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>How to be wise!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/how-to-be-wise.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-15T15:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-09-15:how-to-be-wise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some people are under endless pursuit all life long, but what are they
after? What I am after?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to gain wisdom over life, since I rejoice when I am capable of
delivering wise opinions, having peculiar views. But how? People say
traveling will definitely broaden your views, which is what I am doing
now, but what if I am a blind traveller, what if what I observe is
superficial, what if I see is not even the truth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply absorbing the existent knowledge will not bring the wisdom since
facts are just facts and history will not normally get back on the same
track. Giving the same knowledge, different people process the
information in different ways, resulting in differing opinions. Some are
wiser than others. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I heard of people wishing for wisdom was at a birthday
party of a woman I encountered when I went to Berlin. She met me on the
plane and offered to drive me to the institue and I happily acceped her
help. Afterwards I was invited for her birthday party. She was around 50
and she said she wants wisdom and that is all what she wants for her
age. It sounded really funny to me at the time, since I am wondering
what is really wisdom? But now I want it too, for my age ...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>War leads to peace!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/war-leads-to-peace.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-15T14:51:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-09-15:war-leads-to-peace.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To a certain extend, war &amp;amp; peace resembles the ever-puzzled question
about chicken and egg. In my humble opinion, human natures has long
decided that peace will never come without a war and peace will not be
maintained without a war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Koreans always like to talk about peaceful reunion with North
Korea. Will that happen? Think of DMZ itself, literally means no
military defense along the 4km boarder but instead, silent defense with
tons of explosives buried underground. I have no intention to blame
South Korean since they have to defend their country somehow especially
North Korean government has never ever moved their eyes from South
Korea. There are 4 discovered tunnels across DMZ, built by North Koreans
and&amp;nbsp; the third one is only 50km from Seoul.&amp;nbsp; Everyday, there are tons of
tourists visiting the tunnels, and automatically it reminds South
Koreans that North Korean government is hostile to them so they need to
be armed to protect themselves so as their country, which they have been
working hard for the last few decades. All the young men have to serve
at least 2 years in the army still. Everyone knows this act is not for
Japanese, nor for Chinese but for the people who are part of their
nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard of a rumor that North Korean leader was paralyzed/dead since he
did not show up on TV for a very important parade, North Korean 60th
anniversary. Then I poped into a small restaurant, sort of documentary
about the North Korean leader was shown on TV. At that moment, I could
not help thinking maybe he is really dead!Umm, what if he is really
dead? Will the peaceful reunion take place? I guess North Koreans will
not mind, but South Koreans will not be happy, since ecnomonically they
are 30 times better than North koreans...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the recent incident of the shot Korean woman, 2 MB president led
Sk government decided to stop all the aids for the North Korean. Not
sure when it will resume, since afterall, the people who are at position
will never suffer from famines but the powerless civilians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mao used to say 'power originates from weapons', which sounds brutal and
non civilized. But let us wish human beings will become wise oneday,
despite there are still so many wars around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to gain wisdom!But how?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Koreans</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/koreans.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-01T15:48:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-09-01:koreans.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like Koreans, since I really appreciate their patriotism, their
diligence and hard working spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with patriotism, there is a huge contrast between nowadays Chinese
and Koreans, since Koreans consider no matter what, made in Korea is the
best, while most of Chinese would think the opposite. Driving in the
road, over 90% of the cars are made in Korea. One of the colleagues at
work even got criticized for purchasing a Japanese car. This 'Korean the
best' spirit is also reflected in the daily life, for example, Korean
beaf would be 3 or 4 times more expensive than American or Australian
beef. The justification behind this would be, Korean beef tastes 10
times better. One thing is that normally, Korean would rather marry
koreans when they have a choice, since most of them consider of keeping
the race/nation pure. Even the Chinese Koreans will not normally marry
Han Chinese, the reason on the appearance will be different living
habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard working, well, what can I say? For me, I am a little drained from
the life here from time to time. 1 hour if not more travel to work,
arriving at office around 9am, working until 7 or 8pm, then at least 1
and half hour travel back. I still have maybe 2 hours for myself for the
daily routine. So how about Korean colleagues, when I leave everyday,
there are still at least 20-30 cars at the parking lot. Most of them
would stay until 10pm at least. The guys who have children will have to
say good night to their wife and children on the phone. For them,
sleeping around everyday 3-4 hours is just normal. Still, many
colleagues use to work for Samsung and they claim that it is already an
improvement since they had to work around 80 hours per week at Samsung.
I do not particularly enjoy this environment of course, but I can not
really complain since I have seldom heard complaint from my colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of reasons, which will make me like Koreans since they
are generally very polite, welcome and warm hearted. At work, they would
very patiently explain things to me if needed even though which means
they have to stay half hour longer for their own work. Also, I
particularly enjoy their history lessons at lunch or coffee/smoking
break. Guess because they are all patriotic so they all know their
history pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I am not Korean, I would never choose to live in this
country if I have a choice. Simply because I am a Chinese and I have
also&amp;nbsp; too much appreciation for my own culture and also work is never
going to be everything for me. I still dream one day I will be able to
do well in the things I would always like to do which I did not have a
chance yet...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time, I will try to record my 10 mins brief Korean history.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>3 countries in 2 weeks!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/3-countries-in-2-weeks.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-07-30T15:10:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-07-30:3-countries-in-2-weeks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From Korea to Holland and a week later, turned around back to China. It
was rather hectic, but nice! Glad to see my family! Everyone is well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ningguo is really changing fast, more and more flats built up and more
and more cars in the street. But there is one thing which does not seem
to change, eating and drinking. Time is not allowed, does not matter,
how about singing Karaoke? Well it was fun! Especially I found quite a
few talented singers at the family from my mum's side. I was really
amazed, the little girl just sang along all the songs which were popular
during the last few years. Wondering how she got time to learn all these
since Chinese education is heel druk! Nevertheless, most of things I
planned got done, visited most of the family even though it was really
boiling hot outside. It was hot, but there were still people working
outside in the heat of the sun, so no reason to complain. But it made me
wonder, what if I had to earn a living that way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seoul is very close to Shanghai. The flight was around one and half
hours. I was excited since my sister was with me on the flight. She was
really excited since it was her first time flying and also first time
going abroad. I really could not remember what it was like when I first
went to UK, apart from the fact it was still light when I got out of
Heathrow around 10pm. Oh yeah, my sister is 20.92, I was 21.5 then. So
more or less around the same age. But I was all alone:) I am trying to
remember hard whether I was excited or nervous at all, maybe not. But
something does pop into my head now, a snakebite, a free drink I was
offered at the students' bar on campus on that very evening. Guess I was
desperate to try something really English then! Another intention I had
was probably to practise my English. I always had that in mind for at
least a year!...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in Korea again, the job certainly gets a little more exciting and
I am definitely busier, which is a good thing. I even got a title of
'project leader'. It is cool but a 'less-than-one-year-experienc'
project leader is just not convincing enough. But so far so good! People
get their job done, I get things more or less under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months to go:)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>My first time at Samsung</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/my-first-time-at-samsung.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-06-23T14:59:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-06-23:my-first-time-at-samsung.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was a customer meeting. I thought there was going to be a lot of
shouting, complaining as I often heard people say 'welcome to hell', so
I was prepared to experience the toughest customers in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were all waiting at the entrance to a meeting room. 15mins later, a
guy showed up and rushed to the meeting room. I guessed meeting would
start soon. He stood by the door, keeping the door open and let ASML
people in one after another. Funny enough, everyone took the seats next
to each other on one side of the meeting room. Apparently, the other
side was for customers. Nevertheless, when the meeting started, only
that guy sat on the other side. ...... (Korean) I did not know at what
moment the meeting started, in fact later I did not know when it would
finish. Now and then I heard a few English words. That was it, the
meeting was in Korean. I was wondering whether my mentor understood
anything since he takes Korean lessons twice a week and also has a
'Korean pillow dictionary'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only impression I had was that the meeting was so long. Plus
waiting, it lasted 2&amp;amp;0.5 hours. I got asked how I enjoyed the meeting,
'too long' was my response since I had nothing else to say. 'You have to
get used to it', I was told. Well, good to know that they are going to
have a reform about the customer meeting soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, nothing exciting, but you got to laugh at the following. I got
washed by the water shooting out of the toilet after the meeting. My
notebook was on the ground, completely soaked. My back was half wet,
since I immediately moved to the side. Nevertheless, my naturally
response was to check where the hell was the shooting from, so my face
and hair was also wet with splashed water. I had to laugh even though
the little toilet cabinet was flooded before I realized what the hell
was going on. The wrong button, apparently I pushed. There are lots of
buttons, but I had no idea which one was for flushing since no English
nor readable signs, so I randomly chose the red one, that was how it
happened. I had to guess the little tube which splashes water out with
quite high pressure is for washing the xxS. So the red button was pushed
again by me, the splashing finally stopped. The best I could do is to
search for a manual a flush. Thank god, the flushing handle is set at a
normal position but I had to leave immediately after that since I do not
want people to witness what has just happened to me. So stupid but
funny!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was my first time at Samsung. By the way, I did not particularly
see many Samsung faces:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh another thing: I am going to try out all the other buttons next time,
but I will close the cover first!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Many bizarre things</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/many-bizarre-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-06-18T16:05:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-06-18:many-bizarre-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here and there, I am sometimes stunned with what people told me and what
I observe. So here goes many bizarre things about Seoul. Really crazy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Meeting: Almost all the college and university students have been
often engaged with an activity called 'meeting', in other words: group
dating. A group of boys and girls of equal numbers meet in the cafe or
pub and sit face to face and start talking. If they like each other,
then they go out separately for a coffee/beer or a walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Booking: similar to meeting, but normally not arranged beforehand.
Location is mostly likely a night club, which is very popular with young
people. Normally the boys who are bored or lonely and would like to chat
up a girl will pay lots of tips to the bar tender or waiter in the club.
The one who got tipped turns into a 'pimp' and start a little bit
searching around. But in the end, he will just grab a girl in their arms
and lead her to sit down at the opposite side of the table where the boy
sits at. Sounds rather bizarre, but I guess the girls expect so even
though they do have to shout out 'No'. Then they just start talking, if
they are kind of interested, they will talk more, otherwise, the girl
might be grabbed to another table and it goes on and on. People say that
all the youngsters are party animals. I sometimes wonder how they
manager everyday with only a few hours sleep and also a lot of alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Samsung face or LG face or finance face ... This is the most amusing
thing I have ever heard. Plastic surgery is a very mature business in
Korea, with almost 80% of the population have changed something to their
face or body. The simplest plastic surgery is to double the eye lids,
which does not take long and it costs less than 500 dollars even.
Appearance somehow matters in our society, but not to the extend that
that you believe you have to make your nose a little larger otherwise
you might have no chance to be offered the job. Nevertheless, some
plastic surgery have some sort of career menus, for example, Samsung
menu, which indicates how your face should look like if you go for an
interview at Samsung. When I heard about this, I start imagining all the
people at Samsung look like clones of each other especially when they
are in their uniforms:) That sounds too dramatic, but people do not want
to look different here, especially young girls, so called 'peer
pressure'. Some girls may not want to change their face, but their
parents would even try to convince them that a cute face is important
for them, since that is the key to a good job and a good marriage in the
future! Gek ouders! My parents possibly kick me out immediately if I go
home with a superstar nose. I was wondering why I thought on the first
day that it is very easy to recognize a Korean girl nowaways.
Nevertheless, they do look modern and pretty and extremely fashionable
in my view:) A few times walking around Gangnam, where most young people
get together or go for blind date, I did feel that I am like a beggar,
since I was in my jeans and hiking shoes. Well, I am an alien afterall,
so I do not care!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) Multifunctional compound. Church with Neon light cross on the top,
then from the top to bottom (not sure whether it has particular order):
food court, bar, disco bar (or health club), sort of shops, office,
office, coffee bar, brothel at the basement. When I heard about this,
the closest connection jumped into my head is the red light district in
Amsterdam. I saw in an old photograph that the girls posed in front of
the window with the church just in front of them. Have to say though,
the business does benefit from the 'God' on the top of them, since they
get tax reduction from the government. I know nothing of the brothel at
the basement, but I know it is illegal, but I guess they do have Mafia
taking care of them. Funny enough, adultery in this country is actually
illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5) 2MB president. Protest after protest, it seems going on and on.
Against American beef, against canal. Funny enough 2MB has only been in
position for 3 month and he has almost 5 years to go! In '2MB' 2 is
chosen because of similar pronunciation; 'MB' is the initial. I was
warned not to get close to them, but I bumped into the canal protest
when I was just wondering around with my lonely planet in hand. It
turned out fun for me, enjoying the Korean rock band playing with the
singer's passionate shouting and jumping, with some strange looking man
wiggling like he is on drug. They were not violent at all and it seems
to me they just enjoy themselves. Guess the beef protesters are more
violent somehow if we believe what we see on TV. Oh, yeah, one of the
colleagues is very proud of the protesters, since he reckons the
protests are the symbol of freedom. So the protesters just enjoy their
freedom too much. This is sort of true, since he mentioned if you
protest 20 years ago, what most likely to happen is 'you disappear'
afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6) Korean men describing how tall is their baby using how long. So when
they would use their hands from left to right to judge how big is their
boy or girl. This is indeed not exaggerating, since in my office, many
of them stay until 9pm, and when they get home, their baby is already
lying in their bed:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may have something more, but getting late now. Thanks to the friends
who told me the stories!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Korean food (continue)</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/korean-food-continue.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-06-16T16:17:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-06-16:korean-food-continue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are certain things I am not sure I would ever want to try even
though I was bragging about my boldness all the time:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow Koreans like to eat things raw, just like japanese or the other
way around depending whether I am talking to a Korean or a Japanese:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sashimi, which is a must have delicasy along the coast. However, if I
google Sashimi on Wikipedia, and it reads as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sashimi&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_cuisine"&gt;Japanese delicacy&lt;/a&gt; primarily consisting of very fresh
raw &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seafood"&gt;seafood&lt;/a&gt;, sliced into thin pieces about 2.5cm (1.0in.) wide by
4.0cm (1.5in.) long by 0.5 cm (0.25in.) thick, but dimensions vary
depending on the type of item and chef, and served with only a dipping
sauce (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soy_sauce"&gt;soy sauce&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wasabi"&gt;wasabi&lt;/a&gt; paste and thinly-sliced &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ginger"&gt;ginger&lt;/a&gt;
root or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ponzu"&gt;ponzu&lt;/a&gt;), and a simple garnish such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perilla"&gt;shiso&lt;/a&gt; and shredded
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daikon"&gt;daikon&lt;/a&gt; radish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Korean still believe Japanese copied from them, but I guess most of
people around the world recognize Sashimi is Japanese. Well, I indeed
asked some Koreans that whether there is a difference. However, there
are indeed some difference. I am trying to summarize from what I have
observed/experienced and also heard from others:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Koreans like to have the raw fish really fresh, which means they
donot even want the fish to be marinated too long in the air. Being
fresh to another extend that, they would rather eat it alive or just
about to pass away or just passed away, for example, most restaurants
prepare the fish (not even sure some of them even belong to fish,
because they look so ugly and strange!) just after you have chosen it or
them from the fish tank. In other words, you made a very wise choice to
deliver them to heaven via a shortcut. The most common eat-it-raw is the
jumping octopus. I have never seen it myself and I am not sure I have
the guts to try it anyway. However, I was told what is actually served
commonly is just the tails of octopus. However, due to 'certain
electricity', those tails are still jumping even though they are
deprived of their main body. Once you bite into it, they immediately
surrend to your teath! Believe it or not, most of people who have ever
had it all told me it is indeed very delicious. If this is not scaring
enough, it does happen that someone just starts biting on the whole
alive octopus, which really makes me shiver when I start imagine it!!
But I do dare to see it if someone dares to try it! So far enough for
Korean sashimi, the only thing I know about Japanese Sashimi, is that it
is a little bit less fresh since Japanese like to eat it when it is aged
in a bit after its death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) I am not totally sure this point is true, but I assume it is true for
now since I have never been to Japan. Koreans seem to eat all kinds of
raw fish even the innards. I have heard that the fishmen sometimes make
big efforts to catch fish from the deep sea, which is a very good sell
in the market. The very common innards served as a starter or part of
the fish plate is from sea cucumber or sea pineapple. To be honest, I
have seen sea pineapples in the market but I took it as some kind of
orange plants which grow underearth. Strange!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Koreans sashimi is served with fresh lettice. So the standard way is
to dip the sliced fish in the soysource mixed with wasabi or chili
source and wrap it in the lettice with a piece of raw garlic or chopped
garlic and a piece of green chili. But Japanese sashimi is only served
with soysource and wasabi. Of course another huge difference is that in
general what ever you have for the main food, it always comes with tons
of various sashimi. Amazing enough, the kimchi which comes before Korean
sachimi, are mainly made with fish, all kinds of fish marinated with
spicy sources. Also, after the main meal, it comes the spicy fish soup
(more like a stock), which is normally made with the leftover fish and
many types of vegs. It is very delicious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) I am sure there are some other differences but I have it caught it so
far! I will follow up on it once I find out more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned Koreans eat it raw, and not just fish though. I have seen
people consume raw beaf, also sliced. The more rare ones are raw liver
(not sure which animal though), also raw horse meat. I heard that some
town is specially famous for serving raw horse meat and it is actually
served with affordable price. Nevertheless, I am not really interested
on this one. Unless, someone, who tells me that he or she wants to eat a
whole horse, wants to keep me accompany:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done with Korean food for now. I have more important things to tell
later.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Korean Food so far</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/korean-food-so-far.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-06-10T15:01:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-06-10:korean-food-so-far.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am daring! If the pots and plates look red, I am definitely going to
try it :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I had stomach pain for the first few days, but I just could not
restrain myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly likely, the people at the restaurants do not speak or understand
English, but I am passionally expressing myself in English + all sorts
of movement with hands all the time. But guess what, it turned out twice
that the waitress was actually Chinese. They are Korean Chinese, one of
the 55 minority races, normally living in the northern provinces of
China. Therefore, their local language is Korean but they do get to
learn Chinese at school. So, I think I will try Chinese next time, maybe
the success rate will be higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the entrance of a restaurant, it often requires you to take off the
shoes. I leanrt that also in one of the books about Korea, so I was
extremely cautions about the choice of socks bearing in mind of the
golden rules: no holes, no socks of different colours:-) The dinning
tables, normally have a big hole in the middle, which is meant for
hotpot (spicy kimchi soup + noodles) on a fire. The height of the tables
is around half a meter, so most of people either sit on their bums with
legs crossed in the front or kneel down with the bums resting on the
legs. I am still not used to it and I could not sit in any of the
gestures for too long. I also had troubles to stand up afterwards. Guess
I need some yoga lessons. The common food for lunch or dinner is
noodle/rice soup or steam pot rice. No matter what you order, the first
dishes they bring to the table are 4-6 kinds of spicy snacks: picked
cabbage/radish (definitely red) + raw pointing green chili (devil)
dipped with salty garlic peanut sauce +&amp;nbsp; one green cooked spinach +
pickled/marinated squid (red) + Tofu (white or brown). I really like
this, since it is so diverse and looks pretty in front of me. Also it is
a very good feeling with a table almost filled up with food in front of
me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koreans are generally very friendly in person, unless you are the vendor
at business.&amp;nbsp; All the Korean&amp;nbsp; colleagues work no less than 50 hours a
week. People generally have smiles on their face and they bow to each
other with the upper body slightly tilting towards the front when they
greet or say bye to each other. It is not too hard for me to put a smile
on my face so I do it always:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I enjoy myself in Korea, but I am not sure I would like to work
here for too long. Since it is just too common for people to devote most
of their time to work. Family naturally falls onto the second position
for most of people. I guess this might be also why Korea thrived since
80s. Nevertheless, their hard working is paid off one way or other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be continued (In Korea)!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Seoul, a lovely city</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/seoul-a-lovely-city.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-06-04T14:48:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-06-04:seoul-a-lovely-city.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having stayed at Eindhove for just 7 days, I was leaving for Seoul
again. Eindhoven, I can not really tell whether I have the home feeling
there, but I did feel joyful to meet some colleagues again. I had dinner
activities all through the week from Monday to Friday but I had to leave
on Friday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a lift to the airport from one of the Korean colleagues who works
in Taiwan. It just happened that he had a transit in Seoul to Taiwan but
on a different flight. However, the two flights were 40 mins apart that
he did not mind taking one of my suitcases for me, since I had 12kg
overweight. I was lucky again! Apparently everybody is aware that we
normally can only carry 20kgs as luggage apart from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess that was a good start. The flight was very smooth, no turbulence,
no robbery. The colleague waited for me and helped me find the bus to
the Novotel in Seoul. The journey was around 80mins. I was very curious
about how it looks like outside but I could hardly keep my eyes open. I
woke up when it entered Seoul area. Very busy, very crowded, traffice
almost stopped, which really reminds me of Shanghai. Skyscrapers,
constructions, people, all over the place. Nevertheless, the hotel is
very nice. My room number is 818, guess that is a special treat for me
since I am a Chinese and Chinese in general loves '8'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to now, I realized that I have not really mentioned anything about
Seoul, since I always like to write a complete story, from beginning to
end. Well, never mind, I will continue some other time since I am a bit
tired. I had a long day: 8:30am - 7:30 at work, up at 6:30:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Night!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Sichuan, how can I help, my beloved people?</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/sichuan-how-can-i-help-my-beloved-people.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-05-19T06:55:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-05-19:sichuan-how-can-i-help-my-beloved-people.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;China was not very lucky this year. From the heavy spring snowfall to
Riots in the west and anti-Olympics-in-China to what now the worst
disaster of the century. Tears could not hold in my eyes when watching
the news on internet. I can not help asking myself, why on earth those
innocent people have to be deprived of the company of the loved family?
Some villages are left completely in ruins. Those children were reading,
smiling, chasing each other just a few minutes ago and now where are
they... They dropped to the earth with their smile and their hope and
also the hope of the entire family. The most resentful scene for me to
see is when the elder crying for the loss of the young. They would cry
for that the ones buried under the earth were themselves instead of
their grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am wordless but tearful. Human beings are tinny in front of mother
earth. People have been living there generation after generation for
many centuries but now all destroyed in a split second. No warning, no
regret, all just happened. I have no resent, since this is nobody's
fault. I used to think China is too big for people to be united but I
was so wrong. We stood up together, swallowing the facts of what has
happened, striking through but we are making progress. People will not
fear, and we will help them to rebuild their home and hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am helpless. I wished so much I could be there but I am a practical
coward. I am in US, enjoying my work and life. I wished I could be there
with them, feel what they feel, live what they live, suffer what they
suffer... but I am here, life is as usual. Maybe I am doing the right
thing, there is no moral judgement. I have to live my normal life
despite I feel the pain of being completely unhelpful when such things
happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family is putting their names done for adopting one orphan from the
region. I support them doing so since I know the child will be loved by
my family and we will try our best to bring her/him up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are donations everywhere all over China. Mother earth is watching
us and we can handle this. No matter how poor they are, they could not
wait to offer the help. I meanwhile feel confident it will all pass.
People's life will resume normal soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best wishes to all the people. Please be strong at all time. I swear
I will be nice to all my family and friends and everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodnight!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Sunny California</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/sunny-california.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-05-19T06:15:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-05-19:sunny-california.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am lying in bed and tomorrow morning I am heading to Arches National
Park. My head is now full of stunning images of those perfectly nature
constructed arches. But now I am going to look back into the good time I
had in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California, which seemed so far away from me and I really could not
believe at first place that I was going to be in California for a
training after half year being with my work at ASML. For this particular
reason, I am hoping so much I will do well in my job for return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California, which is sunny and liberal. Sunny, since it almost does not
rain at all past January and February. Liberal, because of its diversity
in population. I had very good examples: 'The L word', in my opinion is
pretty much a rated lesbian TV Soap. If this is not convincing enough,
how about getting a rental car without presenting a physical driving
license but a few copies of it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French are known for their pride. They are proud of their food, culture,
land scape even their non-articulacy with strong French accent when
speaking a foreign language. I start wondering whether the people who
reside in California have similar type of pride. Let us see. Food: 'Oh,
boy' (a funny expression Americans use a lot), you can find almost any
nation's authentic food here. The population is diverse, there is no
necessity to adapt the taste of food to a particular nation. Culture:
diverse! Strong community of Chinese, Vietnamese, Mexican and Spanish...
Land scape: sunny beach + snowing mountain at the same season. Language:
English + Spanish! So a Californian will for sure beats a French in
pride competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for attractions, there are loads of choices. Mine is simple and neat!
A few weekend trips: Yosemite-&amp;gt;Monterey, Big Sur-&amp;gt;San Francisco,
Napa-&amp;gt;San Franciso. Each visit was short, no way being comprehensive but
kind of spiritual. Yosemite, the scene in my opinion is close to
Huangshan Mountain even though the latter does not possess the grand
water falls. Of course the plantation is rather different. The Road
towards the Giant Sequoia was closed for traffic due to heavy snow, but
it did not stop vistors budging through the snow. Paul, Li and I,
decided to run since it is hard to walk straight on the snow trail
anyway. Falling over, standing up, falling over again... My shoes, they
were total soaked, sweat + melted snow + mud. But we were determined to
find the Giant giant Sequoia in the deep forest and of course we made
it. It was all worth it!! The delight at the end of the trip was a treat
of a Chinese buffet. That was really delicious:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Where are you going', 'Big Sur', 'Where? where is that', '90 miles from
here', 'what is there', 'well, forest, ocean, beach...', 'sounds great,
come on then...' we picked up a hitch hiker and he wanted to go to Big
Sur. Where were we going? We wanted to go to Monterey but what the hell,
let us just drive to Big Sur, since we were solely tourists, does not
matter! Well, that is a good few hours driving of 90 miles, since the
route 'high way #1' is winding through the mountains along the Ocean. I
had to say I really enjoyed the driving though, definately the way I
wanted when I first decided to go on highway '1'. Beautiful wild beach
with cliffs, rocky islands and wild plantation, a complete work out for
my new Nikon D60. Tons of 4M pictures, which took me a while to sort
out. Crazy, too dark, too bright, another angle, another pose. Hard to
imagine if it was 5-10 year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;San Francisco airport, I was so excited to meet my fiance after 3 months
without seeing each other. Ralf is still the same, only a bit slimmer
than before, guess a 'vegetarian diet' works quite well on him. I was so
anxious also excited for this moment, but afterall I could not throw
myself into him when I saw him. Well, we acknowledged each other's
feelings. Jing is still Jing, there is something which does not seeem to
change or improve, clumsy and not well organized. It took us a while to
find my rental car. I was so sorry but on the other hand, I could also
give myself an grand excuese that I was desperate to see Ralf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the plan, we parked our car at the airport and took the
metro to the hotel I booked at the Union Square, which is located quite
in the center of San Francisco. It was funny though there were two
westin hotel apparently. At first, we walked into the wrong one feeling
well under-addressed, which apparently is a little of higher class. But
we were glad that was the wrong one. I felt much more comfortable to be
in a reasonable mid-class hotel:) In the end, we got to the right one
and we were offered a room on 37th floor with 270 degree view. Looking
through the window, we can see Alctraz right in the front and also tons
of buildings sitting on the wavy gound of San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time always flies but sometimes you do feel it passes quicker than
another. What is left is sweet memories and dreams. Then life is running
into normal. Working, talking, sleeping, sightseeing, excercising... but
we both have fun and most importantly we keep on encouraging each other
and thinking/caring about each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sunny California had to draw an end too. I was ready to leave but I
told myself that it is a nice place and maybe Ralf and me can find jobs
there and live there for sometime in the future. Afterall, it is one of
the most liberal, most diverse, highest pay states in US and also you
can find best Chinese food there outside China:)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dresden-San Jose: homeless Jing</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/dresden-san-jose-homeless-jing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-04-20T06:57:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-04-20:dresden-san-jose-homeless-jing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I dedicate my Saturday afternoon and evening to my corner blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping I could make better use of my non-office hours, but
sometimes I could not really draw a line between work and non-work. When
life comes to a 'work-sleep-work' pattern, one needs to think better
whether there is anything more you would like to have. Ralf and me both
share the same work ethic, but from time to time we need to alarm
ourselves to dedicate ourselves to some other stuff. For example, I need
to update my blog for my loyal readers:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I have started my TSLH (Travel-Suitcase Live-Hotel) life
since I first went to Dresden on Feb 11th. But officially I only became
homeless after my Dresden trip. March 15th, a marvelous day, I, with
help from Joost and Corry, moved out of my temporary home for less than
1.5 months at Erwin's attic. Sunday, Mar 16th, Olga drove me to Schiphol
and I started my journey to US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Dresden for 5 weeks. People like to say Dresden (Florence on
the Elbe) is built on ruins because of the blanket bombing close to the
end of second world war by British air force and United States Army Air
Force. This bombing still remains controversial since the war was about
to end anyway at the time. The rumor went around as the British did not
want the Russian to enjoy too much on the German ground. Nevertheless,
Dresden is still entitled as one of the most important historical and
cultural city and it attracts from all over the world. Of course, I
would not want to miss my chance either. During the time being there, I
walked around Altstadt (Old town) many times and dined at Neustadt
almost all the time. Altstadt has Frauenkirche, Procession of Dukes
(mural), Hofkirche, Semper Oper Haus with the statue of King John of
Saxony in the front , Zwinger and so on. Frauenkirche was completely
destroyed and the restoration (reconstruction) was accomplished in 2004.
I was not amazed by the church itself since I have seen so many more
magnificent churches in other parts of Europe, however I appreciate the
efforts the public has put in to restore the the church to its original
stand. Procession of Dukes depicts every ruler of Saxony from the middle
ages to the Prussian expansion. I visited the Zwinger for the first time
at dusk. There is a garden inside surrounded by four wings which house
the museum of classic or traditional art and the armory. The other day,
Fei and I were passionate enough to purchase a yearly pass for access to
almost all the museums in Dresden. I had to admit that I only used it on
that day and fortunately the yearly pass was not too costly afterall.
Another attraction which the supervisor brought us to is the 360 degree
panorama painting in the Panometer, which was based on the scene of
Dresden around 200 years ago. Inside, you can go all the way up to the
center tower and enjoy the view of Dresden from dawn to dusk with the
lighting effect. Among all of these, my favourite is the Zwinger and the
Panometer painting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not really lonely during the time in Dresden. I went out with Hans
for dinner almost every evening since he is bothered to cook either.
Moreover we have a very hospitable supervisor, who occasionally invited
us out for coma safe (coma drinking). They are good drinkers and also
party animals. A few times, I escaped to Fei's flat and sat around her
stove enjoying the hot pot. Delicious! As for the food, I had to mention
my on-fire experience at Devil's kitchen at Neustat. In the beginning, I
was not amazed by the spiceness of the food so the restaurant owner was
so kind to offer me some spice which I believe is &lt;strong&gt;Habanero,&lt;/strong&gt;bell
shaped devil which puts my throat and stomach instantly on fire. The
restaurant owner felt so sorry when I was tearfully hopping around but
he did not anticipate I was stupid enough to throw the whole piece into
my mouth just like a piece of snack. What an experience! However, this
did not cool my fever for spicy food at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fei and I also planned a trip to Prague. It is certainly worth it.
Prague is one of those cities you have to explore on foot, full of
stunning surprises. We set our feet across the Vltava river over the
Charles' bridge towards the biggest castle in the world ' Prague
Castle'. On the Charles' bridge, there are a lot of artistic performance
such as bridge band, puppet show, portrait drawing and so on. Prague
Castle is sitting up the hill to present its status. We did not have a
chance to enter the castle since the queue was just too long. Instead,
we visited St George Church, old royal palace and golden all the tiny
Gift shops, which I liked most:) On the other side of Vltava river we
visited old town square. We bumped into some Czech performance at the
center square and tried some local delicacies, also admired the
astronomical clock. By chance, we also run into Jan Saudek's photo
exhibition next to the old town square , which satisfied my vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is more or less about my Dresden trip. It is hard to put every
detail in words but I am trying my best! If you would like to add more
about the history of the city please do so! I would also love to know
more it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>My around-the-world plan!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/my-around-the-world-plan.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-13T00:24:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-01-13:my-around-the-world-plan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have had another talk with my manager the other day. Something went
well, something went all right, something made me cautious about the way
of talking to managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I have got an idea where I am going to be for the next few
months. Not for sure, but most likely. Somehow by coincidence, I am
going to follow part of Ralf's traces again. Beginning of February, I
will be in San Jose, California for AMAT training, which is planned by
myself for 5 weeks. April, maybe another few weeks in Dresden, since
there are two fabs there, Qimonda and AMD. May, Lehi in Utah, June in
Singapore or somewhere else in Asia...Also planning one weekend trip
with Holloway buddies in Barcelona sometime in March or April!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary I gave for my last 3 months at the meeting is rather brief:
I am happy with my progress and especially I feel my learning curve
still has a positive slope. My wish for the future is to learn as much
as I can and to welcome my first start-up project in June or May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite good stories, I also realized I still could not overcome my
nerve-tightening habit when talking in front of people. I was aware of
this when I was in university and thought it had gone better, but
somehow still there. Guess more practice is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From time to time, I would like to impress Ralf how good ASML is, so
wishing that he would like to join in ASML after his stay in US:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New year, new plan. Being confident, being professional, being myself
and being cool. The definition of being cool in my opinion is to be
free, to be kind, to be funny, to be inteligently stupid (for example,
taking a wrong bus, or getting off at the wrong stop and being delivered
home by pizza delivery people), to be open-minded, to be wise!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People say: A smile on the face, things become easier!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish you happy everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I do not have to be too busy to write a post!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/i-do-not-have-to-be-too-busy-to-write-a-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-15T21:23:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-12-15:i-do-not-have-to-be-too-busy-to-write-a-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you can tell that this blog is not updated again for sometime. Being
busy is such a grand excuse I always give myself. Really, I do not have
to be so busy and all the time I feel so hectic but on what? I do have
to learn tons of stuff but there will be never an end. Slow down the
pace, maybe everything will look better, who knows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Xmas present, my best gift will be a method to gain wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come back later, feeling cold now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to learn Dutch on TV in bed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Sorry for this crap post, promise will write something nice soon.)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Learning how to live!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/learning-how-to-live.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-21T19:36:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-10-21:learning-how-to-live.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The title may sound strange but does really&amp;nbsp;everyone in this world know
how to live. I am certainly the exception. We were born for life. Some
people strive for life, some people live the life&amp;nbsp;but&amp;nbsp;other people live
just because they are alive. If I am really bitter about myself, I&amp;nbsp;fit
into the last category better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the first day of life, there is the genuine cruel unfairness,
materialistically&amp;nbsp; or mentally.&amp;nbsp;Based on what I have experienced and
observed,&amp;nbsp;people generally&amp;nbsp;know to&amp;nbsp;how to live better when they are
materialistically satisfied. It makes sense, when you are struggling to
live (to maintain your body in shape), you will not have&amp;nbsp;left-over
energy to live better. Most of people in developing countries live in
this way, including some of my beloved families. They including me, are
used to strive for life because&amp;nbsp;they were born and raised this way. I am
far more satisfied materialistically but still how can I live better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to learn to&amp;nbsp;drive, to speak a foreign language, to play
tennis, to learn whatever other people have done, but how can we learn
how to live. People's life are made and there is no ideal&amp;nbsp;model
but&amp;nbsp;inevitaly people influence each other. I appreciate some people's
way of life but&amp;nbsp;simply I can not live like that because I do not own
that kind of mind set. Something&amp;nbsp;growing deeply in me would not let me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To suffer, to&amp;nbsp;enjoy, to learn...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ralf and me.</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/ralf-and-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-13T10:38:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-10-13:ralf-and-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ralf is in sleep now. By now I automatically deduct my time by 6 hours.
We talked everyday so far, and I am all alone so is he. We both have to
make new friends and build up a new social circle. However, I am not in
a hurry, just have too much to do at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am definitely not&amp;nbsp;freaked out by the&amp;nbsp;distance yet. Well, I know it is
a daring comment because we&amp;nbsp;have been only apart for 4 days.
But&amp;nbsp;amazingly, lots of small sweet details traced back from time to time
in my mind. Is the distance a trigger I am not so sure, but I like the
feelings. It was much harder&amp;nbsp;for me before he left and for now I just
have to accept it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jing&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>So long ago!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/so-long-ago.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-13T10:23:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-10-13:so-long-ago.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, everyone. This web almost becomes obsolete&amp;nbsp;so now I am going to
rescue it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am nowhere close to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;a writer&amp;nbsp;and really sometimes it is very hard
to have a peaceful mind to sit down actually writing some genuine
thought. It also could be I do not have any&amp;nbsp; thought, but believe me we
are thinking, judging or evaluating all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myself. I never stopped evaluating myself all the time. Generally
speaking, I do not have so much confidence in myself. Well, I'd better
express it in a more clear fashion. Maybe because of my goal is too
high, it causes stress and frustration, which leads to&amp;nbsp;a reduction of my
confidence. But I can not help at this point because I believe 10 times
more efforts will always compensate for less intelligence. When I was in
high school, I was told by one of the seniors that he always used the
back of a knife to chop a tree down. Of course then he spent much more
efforts than the people who used the sharp side. This is a bit
exaggerating, but it is kind of hitting the point. I am always willing
to spend more efforts to achieve the goal because I believe I have to.
Guess what, it works so far. I managed to attend a good university in
China, then accomplished my PhD on time even though I still felt I could
have failed if I was in the Netherlands or Finland. Whatever, now I
started my new profession, I just have to work on and work harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASML. I felt cool so far about my job. My colleagues are experienced,
motivated and hard working. Most importantly, they are so willing to
explain things in a simple case. Well, here you go. I am the least
experienced in the whole group and there is so much I have no clue what
is all about. Do they expect me to know all this already? Am I confident
now that I will catch it up soon? There is one solution: trying and
trying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, hope you are not bored by now. Have a good day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jing&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Free music!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/free-music.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-08-03T14:57:00+02:00</updated><author><name>rgommers</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-08-03:free-music.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well first I'll say hi to everyone, since this is my first post and I'm
happy to share Jing's blog. Now on topic: do you want some great free
music? Then go &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://magnatune.com/freemusic"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Magnatune&lt;/strong&gt; is a great music site, I've bought
several albums from them already. Now they've decided to give an album
away for free each month, so try it and download if you like it! Also,
if you buy anything you can legally give three more copies away to your
friends. So if you read this leave a comment and you're next on the list
for that:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well it's almost weekend, so I'm off to play badminton with Jing and
some friends. And maybe make a trip to Windsor. And enjoy one of the
last weekends we'll have here in the UK (which is good and bad at the
same time)......&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ralf&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Mijn moeder is vandaag jarig-sth about my family!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/mijn-moeder-is-vandaag-jarig-sth-about-my-family.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-30T23:23:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-30:mijn-moeder-is-vandaag-jarig-sth-about-my-family.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is my mum's birthday. I called her and she was apprently surprised
I even remembered it was her birthday. One thing is because like many
other Chinese including me, my mum has a date in lunar calenda for her
birthday and on the other hand, really I did not consiciously remind
myself for the birthdays because I hardly remembered we ever celebrated
the birthdays. In Asian culture, birthday does not seem to be as
important as in western culture. I have learnt in my Dutch book that
every ducth family has a birthday calenda in their toilet. However, I
could tell how happy my mum was when I called her for this even though
it was just a couple of words from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been heartily expressive towards my family, maybe because
we are never used to it. My father is a rather quiet person and it
seemed to me we had more comminications on the phone rather than face to
face. I was always a bit confused by my father's silence when he came to
pick me up at the bus stop when I had traveled from Shanghai to my home,
because he was desperately calling me home immediately after the holiday
started. So everytime I was worried that something upsetting had
happened. It was just like that but I have never been convinced that he
does not need to communicate with us. I am still trying to find a way to
talk to my father heart to heart. My mum and me always talk a lot. The
thing we care most about each other is that whether we are happy or
whether we are healthy. My mum has had very tough experiences in her
life. She was not the oldest but it just happened that she had to quit
her study in order to take care of my grandma in hospital and also her
younger siblings. She did have resentment sometimes but she could not
blame anyone for this. She never likes me to tell people that she could
not read or write much. But I always tell her there is nothing to be
ashamed of, because the time made it and she sacrificed hers for my
uncle, my aunt and her mum. However she is proud of my sister and me
that we can have the oppotunity to be well educated, especially I am
going to be a PhD and people say I have all made it up for her. The
world I share with my mum is mainly her circle and a small part of mine.
But we do not mind because we always have lots of tiny things to talk
about. My sister, I was protective of her when she was small then we
fought and argued all the time until finally I had to leave for
university. We missed each so much then! It was partially my fault to
fight or argue with her, because I cared too much of her behaviors to
push her too much only until one day I realized that she has her own
view and I can not really tell her what she should not or should have
done. By now, I am sometimes suggestively telling her what I think it is
better and occasionally reminding her to work a bit harder and not waste
too much time. Actually she likes my encouragement and she trusts me
much more than before. She is in Xiamen (a city on the eastern coste of
China) now with one of my cousins. It is kind of her first trip without
older-generation's supervision and I am so happy for this even though my
father still believed they went with my uncle otherwise this trip could
not have happened. It will get better! To end, happy birthday to my dear
mum.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I confess: I do not like losing, neither always winning!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/i-confess-i-do-not-like-losing-neither-always-winning.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-19T22:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-19:i-confess-i-do-not-like-losing-neither-always-winning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Physics badminton is expanding. Originally I have got together four
people and played on a weekly basis. Now we have 8 people playing on two
courts and 2 to 3 times a week. It is not the first time I realize I do
not like losing. My nerve naturally gets tightened when I am on a losing
track and I can not even squeeze a smile out of my face. People must
have believed I am far too serious. It is not a pleasant feeling but the
thing I am concerned most is that it may not be pleasant for others. On
the other hand, when Aya and me played as the Asian team, we always won
over the European team: Michele and Ben. I definitely lost interest
after a little while because it was not enough challenge. The right
altitude I believe should be: Feel rejoiced when winning; control better
when losing. Afterall, no failure, no progress! Just like No pain, No
gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not wish to be a bad loser!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Things I will have to do!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/things-i-will-have-to-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-16T17:18:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-16:things-i-will-have-to-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New era, new plans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things I always wanted to do and did not manage to do
them well, such as tennis, guitar, Spanish, Dutch and Swimming. I will
have to learn Dutch well since I will be living there since October. I
will have to learn swimming well since I was nearly drowned in the sea.
I will have to learn guitar well, since I always wish to impress Ralf
with my music. Spanish, since I always wish to travel around the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Hello, people!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-14T10:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-14:hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, Jing's Corner is a symbol of beginning of new era of my life. This
summer is fruitful, which is the special reason to set up this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf's job offer from MIT was a good start of this new era. After this
event, things move quite rapidly for him. Tomorrow (17/07/2007), he is
going to be a real Doctor of Philosophy in physics even though he feels
like a doctor long ago. I admire him for his confidence. He submitted a
hard copy of his thesis to the Senate house because he believed that was
it and he was not expecting any changes to his thesis by his examiners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, things are moving forward definitely even though it was not as
fast. But i have nothing to complain about. I got my first job offer
ever in my life on July 11th, which was a date mixed with excitement and
confusion. I am going to be an engineer working for ASML, which is the
world leading lithography company. This means I can proudly mark myself
as a young professional in semiconductor industry. Fine, that sounds
great but how about the next two years or &amp;gt; two years apart from my
love. I am not worried about myself but Ralf because I will have enough
time to take care of myself. Ralf is the person who has to work at least
50 hours per week! &lt;strong&gt;To Ralf, please do not indulge yourself with
America burgers or microwave food!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we will adapt ourself to the distance. (Chinese) People
say that 距离产生美 (Distance makes perfect) . Sure, no doubt everything
has its beautiful side. I will be staying at our home in Eindhoven, and
Ralf will be on a long-term business&amp;nbsp; trip in Boston. Time will fly by
and the proof will find its way in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>