<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jing's Corner</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/</id><updated>2013-03-31T19:46:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Sometimes you just feel like writing something down</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/sometimes-you-just-feel-like-writing-something-down.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-31T19:46:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-03-31:sometimes-you-just-feel-like-writing-something-down.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been a long time that I actually start writing something down. It
did occur to me a few times before that I wanted to write something down
to reflect upon what I had been doing, but it did not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So actually I am pretty happy to find out my wordpress account still
works, which offers means when I do want to record something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often say to people 'that is really cool and I want to do it too
someday'. I have a lot of 'wants'. Sometimes I will just have to
translate the 'want' into actions, then it actually can become true.
Looking at my progress of keeping up the goals I set this year for
myself over the first quarter, I would say I have had a slow start so
far. The good thing is that I shall still look forward. With the weather
getting better and the day getting longer, I will have much more passion
to do more sports outside. So it is not yet too late to catch up. Easier
said than done, I will just have to check up on myself once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you all later.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Forwarded: My Farewell Letter</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/forwarded-my-farewell-letter.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-28T16:55:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2011-06-28:forwarded-my-farewell-letter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Actually I did write something. Below is my farewell letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Fortimo is one of Philips brand for LED lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HELLOOOO AND GOODBYE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, there,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many of you have already known, today is my last day &amp;#64; Shanghai
office. Very complicated feelings often occur to me at such moments.
Therefore, I have recorded below a short conversation I had with Ms
Fortimoie Shanghai (first name: Fortimoie) when I was still calm and
sober.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: So why do you leave me?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: please allow me to apologize first of all. It was not my
intention to leave you but I had to make this decision because my
laogong relocated to the Netherlands.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: I see, that makes me feel slightly better. I thought you do
not like me:(.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: That is absolutely not the case. I do enjoy working with you, it
is such a dynamic environment and it is full of passion and challenges.
Also, you have so many fans around the whole Asia pacific region. It is
really a great pleasure to have been working here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: I am happy you enjoyed it. What are you going to do&amp;nbsp; next?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: Guess what, I am going to work for one of your relatives, who is
also one of your fans but located at 120degs across the globe. His name
is OEM EMEA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: Oh, that is nice, I am glad you are still in the same world
as me then. Do you think you will come back in the future?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: Yeah, I would definitely like to in the future when there is a
good opportunity. So please do not forget about me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: That is good. But… but it is kind of sad still.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jing: Ah, don’t be sad. Let me tell you a joke: ‘there's a family of
tomatoes walking down the street: the daddy tomato, the mommy tomato and
the baby tomato. The daddy tomato is becoming more and more annoyed with
the baby tomato because the baby tomato is taking its time dragging his
feet looking at everything. so finally the daddy tomato turns around and
walks back to where the baby tomato is &amp;amp; steps &amp;amp; smuches the baby tomato
&amp;amp; screams: &amp;quot;Ketchup!&amp;quot;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortimoie: hahaha, fine, you can turn off your laptop and get ready to
leave, take care … :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day. Wish you all the best all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jing&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I am back to Holland</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/i-am-back-to-holland.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-28T16:48:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2011-06-28:i-am-back-to-holland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been such a long time that I ever wrote anything. When I read the
last post on this blog,&amp;nbsp; I was questioning myself whether I am the
person who wrote that. But I had excuses since Wordpress, Facebook,
Twitter are all blocked in China. Now it is the chance, since I just
moved back to China after about 1.5 years living in Shanghai. I am
excited in a way because I consider it is a start of a new life again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday, Ralf and I went hiking around Drie Land Pont and we
happened to be at the highest point of the Netherlands: 327.5m. I was
quite excited by the fact that it is highEST. The important matter of
fact here is that I am generally impressed by first or est, such as
most, best, tallest, fastest and so on. Then I told Ralf, how about we
have an EST day every week. Once we run out of good ideas of being
..est, we can just eat most hamburgers for example. While I am writing
this down, trust me that I am really getting excited about this idea :)
If this comes true, I will never have a problem in finding materials for
blogging anymore. Whoever reads this can of course contribute to my EST
idea. I will just try it out at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BTW: we learnt at the highest point of the Netherlands: the Dire land
pont was once upon a time Fier Land Pont. The 4th land was Sc.., which
then became part of Belgium. I got to learn better the history of the
Netherlands and the neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome myself to the Netherlands again!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Job-Life</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/job-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-27T00:08:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2009-03-27:job-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is rather not an easy topic for the moment. Every single day in the
past months, it appeared in the news that thousands people get laid off.
Though I am not panic about myself, but such news rather made me at
unease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking a lot about what Steve Jobs spoke in the speech
given to Stanford 'As with all matters of the heart, you'll know when
you find it, and like any great relationship it just gets better and
better as the years roll on. So keep looking. Don't settle.' Job
occupies the biggest portion of life since I usually disregard sleeping
as a part unless I found some solutions or came across some joyful
events in my dream, which is rather rare for me anyway. I am no way near
settled with my job but on the other hand, I have not really kept
looking. Where do I exactly stand and where should I head to, I do not
have a clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do people see their jobs? It is hard to judge one by one. However,
there are several possibilities. Some people hate their job, it is
deemed that life is much less pleasant than it should be until one day
the limit is reached and they quit; some people step out of it, they may
enjoy their work, may not, but they make themselves aware that work is
just part of the deal of life. So they do their job and move on with
life, which apparently contradicts with what Steve said. I would not
consider this wrong since not everyone is as lucky that they know what
exactly they are fascinated with. I certainly donot know what would be
my ideal job for life. Then comes the lucky ones, they love their jobs
and they are excited about their work. I do not know what more to
comment but to admire such gurus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mainland China and many other developing countries, it is safe to
say, many people work for life. No work, no sustainable life at all.
Though I am like quite like that, but I donot think I am completely
immune from the thought of work for life. People have to work to survive
in whichever case, but some people can choose what work to do, while
some donot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still searching where I am. Maybe I could adopt some thought or
attitude of others to make job both easy and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>another year - 1st post of 2009</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/another-year-1st-post-of-2009.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-01-17T13:53:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2009-01-17:another-year-1st-post-of-2009.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am now sitting in a Starbucks, waiting for the movie 'Australia' to be
screened within a couple of hours on the top floor of this department
store. In fact, I have been here for most of the afternoon reading. The
weather was good and enough sunshine to keep me warm sitting outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year 2008 is gone and immediately followed by year 2009. Meanwhile so
many years have past in the history of human beings. All what I could
possibly know about the past relies in the books, or occasionally
historical films and the rest I have to depend on my own imagination.
People have to always look forward since the past can not be changed but
somehow luckily you still have a little control over your future.
Nevertheless, the past brought you experience and we can all learn about
our past and hopefully wisdom will be built up with the appearance of
the wrinkles at the corner of your deepening eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking into my past, it has been smooth and almost frustration free
apart from occasional modern man-made fuss, which is not worth to
mention. 4 years in university followed by 4 years in UK plus one year
with a job, 9 years of life has past but I obtained a lot (hopefully)
from the life and have got what is left all stays in my mind. However,
these many years, I still have not been able to follow the fashion of
the modern society. I still do not care what I am not used to care, such
as dresses, skin protection, all kinds of beauty treatment, fashion and
so on. I am looking around me now, the girls with shopping bags are in
mini-skirt, high heels, curly hair, nicely curved eye-brow ... I start
wondering why I am not like that. Is there anything missing in my life
or I cling to my past no matter what, or I still indulge myself stupidly
just to mark myself different from others. Fortunately it is never good
to judge your own life based on other peoples' standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to my last year, I have been without a home since mid Feb
and ever since I stayed most of the 365 days in a hotel room. How do I
feel? I think it is all right since I chose the job and I wanted to try
what I and most of other people have not tried. But am I really enjoying
it? It is lonely and you end up with a lot of time which you have to
fill it in all by yourself. Nevertheless, I have seen a bit of different
parts of the world so far and most importantly, I have entered the unit
of the society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, I have completely forgotten what I originally wanted to write in
this post. Well, whatever, I have to go for my movie now.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>It is almost another year</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/it-is-almost-another-year.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-20T17:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-12-20:it-is-almost-another-year.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year almost comes to an end and I start wondering what is going to
be my new year's resolution. For the last few years, I always tried to
have one but whether it really worked has never been&amp;nbsp; checked. However,
now I think about it but I already forgot what was my last year's
resolution. I kind of know what I wish but just not sure how to make it
happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is kind of hard to summarize what I have done for this whole year but
I will categorize my activities into the following: the things I had to
do, the things I wanted to do and the things I wanted to do but not yet
done. So now, the things I had to do, such as eating, cleaning, going to
work, sleeping and you name it; since you have to do them, so it seems
rather important but on the other hand can be much less fun. The things
I wanted to do, such as doing my job seriously, keeping this blog,
learning swimming, being conscious what is going on in this world and of
course the most important thing both Ralf and I wanted: becoming really
family. Though the life after marriage has not really changed yet, but
we are the family and we know we will hold on together no matter what
difficulties we are going to encounter. As for the things I wanted to do
but not yet done, I am afraid the list can go on forever. But I will
name a few which are on top of my head since they are of importance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First one, I should have better control when I am down. It is hard to
admit but I do think I am a little self-centered, since once I am
unhappy or distressed, my thought can be so negative which may impact
others. Since I mention this, I will take the opportunity to apologize
to Ralf because he suffered most when I was down. It is always
afterwards I regret I should have better control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is that to help the poor better. I do not really know how
to address this issue since my capability is small though I wish so much
I can make a change. I am easily touched but also easily forget. When I
am touched, resentment is meanwhile produced, why life has to be so
unfair and why the gap is getting larger all the time. It is a really
meaningless complaint, since sxxt happens all the time at some parts of
the world. However, little effort is better than nothing and I will bear
this in mind, hope you do as well, dear readers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is for sure now another day, so nothing left but sleepiness :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Howard hotel, Hsinchu.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Jing’s family</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/jings-family-migrated-from-the-wedding-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-20T15:16:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-11-20:jings-family-migrated-from-the-wedding-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;My parents have been living in Ningguo for all their life so far and they&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;intend to stay in Ningguo for the rest of their life. I moved out of&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;home when I started university in Shanghai in the year of 1999 and my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;sister entered university in 2005.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;We have moved 6 times within Ningguo. From a big house in Red Star&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;village to a tiny semi-attached house in Feng Xing village, where the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;steel ball factory my father worked relocated. It is a house but&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;actually it only has one kitchen and one living room downstairs, and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;one bedroom with two beds and a 14-inch colour TV upstairs. I did not&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;recall any bad memories for staying in this little containment, except&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;for my sister being kicked out of the bed a few times during the three&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;years we stayed there. I still vividly remember there were 8 households&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;in a row and my house was the first in the row. The neighbours are&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;still very good friends of my family, especially the kids of my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;sister’s age.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;The living area of the factory was divided into different parts and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;each part has one unique type of accommodation, such as the tiny little&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;double-floor house (step 1), two-bedroom bungalow (step 2), two-bedroom&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;apartment (step 3), three-bedroom apartment (step 4). The people who&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;worked in sales were generally better off in the factory so they may&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;jump in steps starting from step 3. It was like a ladder for my family,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;we experienced step 1 to step 3 and then we moved out of the factory&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;because my father started his own business in 1997. After step 3, we&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;went back to a similar step 1 again. Because my father quited his job,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;we had to move out immediately so we end up in a temporary match box&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;type compound again. It was simple, just two big rooms so we could be a&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;bit creative in how to make into a home for four. My parent’s bedroom&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;occupy one room, and the other we divided it into a kitchen and the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;bedroom for me and my sister. The advantage about this accommodation is&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;that it is in the city center and very close to my school but the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;disadvantage is that it is right below a dancing and Karaoke salon,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;which normally runs until 1am at earliest. I remembered by then a few&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;sleepless night for me and my sister. If we were lucky, sometimes a&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;nice song with a nice tune or close to the tune, but most of time ended&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;up with some shouting completely out of tune. However, I missed so much&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;the time when my sister and I went to the small restaurant after my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;school at night. We would always spend 5 yuan (50 cents) for a plate of&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;stir-fried sliced potato and two bows of plain rice or some spicy&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;noodles before we could go to sleep after the dancing salon stopped its&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;business.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Time flew as it is now. We moved to our new flat afterwards and my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;father’s business of steel ball mold seemed to move on the right track&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;and most importantly we did not have to suffer midnight shouting&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;anymore. My father always told us if he had not quited his job in that&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;factory, he would have never afforded me and my sister both going to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;universities. Of course he would not have afforded to built a house for&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;our family, nor any big purchase he made for the house. Also thanks to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;him, I was able to start my adventure in a foreign country via studying&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;in UK as my first stop. To be honest, I did not mean to break my&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;promise to my father that I would go back home after my MSc study in&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Nano physics, but the study was so short that I simply did not have&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;enough of it so I stayed for my PhD with financial support from the UK&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;government and the university, which turned out to be the best choice&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;so far of my life otherwise this blog would not have existed at the&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;first place.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;I always believe in the butterfly effect, which means a small effect&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;can lead to a big event in the future. In this case, if Ralf had not&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;elbowed me in the conference hall when I spontaneously took the sit&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;next to him, he would not have asked for my hand under the statue at&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;the far end opposite the Windsor Castle.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;That is about it! But of course, I have lots of uncles and aunts and&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;dozens of cousins and two grandmothers. Amazingly I feel very close to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;almost all of them. Guess it is because we all live close together,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;which means half an hour at most walking distance. Whenever I go home,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;there will be always big get-togethers all the time. One get-together&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;is never enough, because in China, who initiates the invitation will&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;pay for the dinner, so everyone wants to take turn to pay, so let us&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;start counting. My mother’s side has on total 6 siblings, same also at&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;my father’s side. so on total 12 dinners to go. This is not all, how&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;about my parents’ friends and our neighbours and my friends.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;Invitations come in chains, one chain after another or chain twisted in&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;another chain, so everyday I or Ralf and I when we go back together,&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;are booked from lunch to dinner if not breakfast! Since Ralf looks so&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;different from a normal Chinese, it made us even more popular! What a&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;phenomenon!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;In China, the elders are mostly supported by their children because&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;there is almost no pension from the government unless the elder retires&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;from a job position within a government or from a government-own&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;factory. Both of my grandmothers have to depend on my parents and all&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;my uncles as well as my aunts. Fortunately my parents and their&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;siblings are not doing too bad, but for some elders, it can be a sever&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;problem. I have seen so many poor eldly people, so I always wanted to&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;build an eldly home sometime in the future.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;So much about my family. They are all lovely people, I really hope you&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;will enjoy their company during the wedding.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>How to be wise!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/how-to-be-wise.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-15T15:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-09-15:how-to-be-wise.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some people are under endless pursuit all life long, but what are they
after? What I am after?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to gain wisdom over life, since I rejoice when I am capable of
delivering wise opinions, having peculiar views. But how? People say
traveling will definitely broaden your views, which is what I am doing
now, but what if I am a blind traveller, what if what I observe is
superficial, what if I see is not even the truth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply absorbing the existent knowledge will not bring the wisdom since
facts are just facts and history will not normally get back on the same
track. Giving the same knowledge, different people process the
information in different ways, resulting in differing opinions. Some are
wiser than others. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I heard of people wishing for wisdom was at a birthday
party of a woman I encountered when I went to Berlin. She met me on the
plane and offered to drive me to the institue and I happily acceped her
help. Afterwards I was invited for her birthday party. She was around 50
and she said she wants wisdom and that is all what she wants for her
age. It sounded really funny to me at the time, since I am wondering
what is really wisdom? But now I want it too, for my age ...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Sichuan, how can I help, my beloved people?</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/sichuan-how-can-i-help-my-beloved-people.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-05-19T06:55:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-05-19:sichuan-how-can-i-help-my-beloved-people.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;China was not very lucky this year. From the heavy spring snowfall to
Riots in the west and anti-Olympics-in-China to what now the worst
disaster of the century. Tears could not hold in my eyes when watching
the news on internet. I can not help asking myself, why on earth those
innocent people have to be deprived of the company of the loved family?
Some villages are left completely in ruins. Those children were reading,
smiling, chasing each other just a few minutes ago and now where are
they... They dropped to the earth with their smile and their hope and
also the hope of the entire family. The most resentful scene for me to
see is when the elder crying for the loss of the young. They would cry
for that the ones buried under the earth were themselves instead of
their grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am wordless but tearful. Human beings are tinny in front of mother
earth. People have been living there generation after generation for
many centuries but now all destroyed in a split second. No warning, no
regret, all just happened. I have no resent, since this is nobody's
fault. I used to think China is too big for people to be united but I
was so wrong. We stood up together, swallowing the facts of what has
happened, striking through but we are making progress. People will not
fear, and we will help them to rebuild their home and hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am helpless. I wished so much I could be there but I am a practical
coward. I am in US, enjoying my work and life. I wished I could be there
with them, feel what they feel, live what they live, suffer what they
suffer... but I am here, life is as usual. Maybe I am doing the right
thing, there is no moral judgement. I have to live my normal life
despite I feel the pain of being completely unhelpful when such things
happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family is putting their names done for adopting one orphan from the
region. I support them doing so since I know the child will be loved by
my family and we will try our best to bring her/him up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are donations everywhere all over China. Mother earth is watching
us and we can handle this. No matter how poor they are, they could not
wait to offer the help. I meanwhile feel confident it will all pass.
People's life will resume normal soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best wishes to all the people. Please be strong at all time. I swear
I will be nice to all my family and friends and everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodnight!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I do not have to be too busy to write a post!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/i-do-not-have-to-be-too-busy-to-write-a-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-12-15T21:23:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-12-15:i-do-not-have-to-be-too-busy-to-write-a-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you can tell that this blog is not updated again for sometime. Being
busy is such a grand excuse I always give myself. Really, I do not have
to be so busy and all the time I feel so hectic but on what? I do have
to learn tons of stuff but there will be never an end. Slow down the
pace, maybe everything will look better, who knows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Xmas present, my best gift will be a method to gain wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come back later, feeling cold now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to learn Dutch on TV in bed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Sorry for this crap post, promise will write something nice soon.)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Learning how to live!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/learning-how-to-live.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-21T19:36:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-10-21:learning-how-to-live.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The title may sound strange but does really&amp;nbsp;everyone in this world know
how to live. I am certainly the exception. We were born for life. Some
people strive for life, some people live the life&amp;nbsp;but&amp;nbsp;other people live
just because they are alive. If I am really bitter about myself, I&amp;nbsp;fit
into the last category better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the first day of life, there is the genuine cruel unfairness,
materialistically&amp;nbsp; or mentally.&amp;nbsp;Based on what I have experienced and
observed,&amp;nbsp;people generally&amp;nbsp;know to&amp;nbsp;how to live better when they are
materialistically satisfied. It makes sense, when you are struggling to
live (to maintain your body in shape), you will not have&amp;nbsp;left-over
energy to live better. Most of people in developing countries live in
this way, including some of my beloved families. They including me, are
used to strive for life because&amp;nbsp;they were born and raised this way. I am
far more satisfied materialistically but still how can I live better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to learn to&amp;nbsp;drive, to speak a foreign language, to play
tennis, to learn whatever other people have done, but how can we learn
how to live. People's life are made and there is no ideal&amp;nbsp;model
but&amp;nbsp;inevitaly people influence each other. I appreciate some people's
way of life but&amp;nbsp;simply I can not live like that because I do not own
that kind of mind set. Something&amp;nbsp;growing deeply in me would not let me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To suffer, to&amp;nbsp;enjoy, to learn...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Ralf and me.</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/ralf-and-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-13T10:38:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-10-13:ralf-and-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ralf is in sleep now. By now I automatically deduct my time by 6 hours.
We talked everyday so far, and I am all alone so is he. We both have to
make new friends and build up a new social circle. However, I am not in
a hurry, just have too much to do at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am definitely not&amp;nbsp;freaked out by the&amp;nbsp;distance yet. Well, I know it is
a daring comment because we&amp;nbsp;have been only apart for 4 days.
But&amp;nbsp;amazingly, lots of small sweet details traced back from time to time
in my mind. Is the distance a trigger I am not so sure, but I like the
feelings. It was much harder&amp;nbsp;for me before he left and for now I just
have to accept it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jing&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>So long ago!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/so-long-ago.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-13T10:23:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-10-13:so-long-ago.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, everyone. This web almost becomes obsolete&amp;nbsp;so now I am going to
rescue it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am nowhere close to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;a writer&amp;nbsp;and really sometimes it is very hard
to have a peaceful mind to sit down actually writing some genuine
thought. It also could be I do not have any&amp;nbsp; thought, but believe me we
are thinking, judging or evaluating all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myself. I never stopped evaluating myself all the time. Generally
speaking, I do not have so much confidence in myself. Well, I'd better
express it in a more clear fashion. Maybe because of my goal is too
high, it causes stress and frustration, which leads to&amp;nbsp;a reduction of my
confidence. But I can not help at this point because I believe 10 times
more efforts will always compensate for less intelligence. When I was in
high school, I was told by one of the seniors that he always used the
back of a knife to chop a tree down. Of course then he spent much more
efforts than the people who used the sharp side. This is a bit
exaggerating, but it is kind of hitting the point. I am always willing
to spend more efforts to achieve the goal because I believe I have to.
Guess what, it works so far. I managed to attend a good university in
China, then accomplished my PhD on time even though I still felt I could
have failed if I was in the Netherlands or Finland. Whatever, now I
started my new profession, I just have to work on and work harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASML. I felt cool so far about my job. My colleagues are experienced,
motivated and hard working. Most importantly, they are so willing to
explain things in a simple case. Well, here you go. I am the least
experienced in the whole group and there is so much I have no clue what
is all about. Do they expect me to know all this already? Am I confident
now that I will catch it up soon? There is one solution: trying and
trying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, hope you are not bored by now. Have a good day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jing&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Free music!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/free-music.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-08-03T14:57:00+02:00</updated><author><name>rgommers</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-08-03:free-music.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well first I'll say hi to everyone, since this is my first post and I'm
happy to share Jing's blog. Now on topic: do you want some great free
music? Then go &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://magnatune.com/freemusic"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Magnatune&lt;/strong&gt; is a great music site, I've bought
several albums from them already. Now they've decided to give an album
away for free each month, so try it and download if you like it! Also,
if you buy anything you can legally give three more copies away to your
friends. So if you read this leave a comment and you're next on the list
for that:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well it's almost weekend, so I'm off to play badminton with Jing and
some friends. And maybe make a trip to Windsor. And enjoy one of the
last weekends we'll have here in the UK (which is good and bad at the
same time)......&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ralf&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Mijn moeder is vandaag jarig-sth about my family!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/mijn-moeder-is-vandaag-jarig-sth-about-my-family.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-30T23:23:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-30:mijn-moeder-is-vandaag-jarig-sth-about-my-family.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is my mum's birthday. I called her and she was apprently surprised
I even remembered it was her birthday. One thing is because like many
other Chinese including me, my mum has a date in lunar calenda for her
birthday and on the other hand, really I did not consiciously remind
myself for the birthdays because I hardly remembered we ever celebrated
the birthdays. In Asian culture, birthday does not seem to be as
important as in western culture. I have learnt in my Dutch book that
every ducth family has a birthday calenda in their toilet. However, I
could tell how happy my mum was when I called her for this even though
it was just a couple of words from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been heartily expressive towards my family, maybe because
we are never used to it. My father is a rather quiet person and it
seemed to me we had more comminications on the phone rather than face to
face. I was always a bit confused by my father's silence when he came to
pick me up at the bus stop when I had traveled from Shanghai to my home,
because he was desperately calling me home immediately after the holiday
started. So everytime I was worried that something upsetting had
happened. It was just like that but I have never been convinced that he
does not need to communicate with us. I am still trying to find a way to
talk to my father heart to heart. My mum and me always talk a lot. The
thing we care most about each other is that whether we are happy or
whether we are healthy. My mum has had very tough experiences in her
life. She was not the oldest but it just happened that she had to quit
her study in order to take care of my grandma in hospital and also her
younger siblings. She did have resentment sometimes but she could not
blame anyone for this. She never likes me to tell people that she could
not read or write much. But I always tell her there is nothing to be
ashamed of, because the time made it and she sacrificed hers for my
uncle, my aunt and her mum. However she is proud of my sister and me
that we can have the oppotunity to be well educated, especially I am
going to be a PhD and people say I have all made it up for her. The
world I share with my mum is mainly her circle and a small part of mine.
But we do not mind because we always have lots of tiny things to talk
about. My sister, I was protective of her when she was small then we
fought and argued all the time until finally I had to leave for
university. We missed each so much then! It was partially my fault to
fight or argue with her, because I cared too much of her behaviors to
push her too much only until one day I realized that she has her own
view and I can not really tell her what she should not or should have
done. By now, I am sometimes suggestively telling her what I think it is
better and occasionally reminding her to work a bit harder and not waste
too much time. Actually she likes my encouragement and she trusts me
much more than before. She is in Xiamen (a city on the eastern coste of
China) now with one of my cousins. It is kind of her first trip without
older-generation's supervision and I am so happy for this even though my
father still believed they went with my uncle otherwise this trip could
not have happened. It will get better! To end, happy birthday to my dear
mum.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>I confess: I do not like losing, neither always winning!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/i-confess-i-do-not-like-losing-neither-always-winning.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-19T22:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-19:i-confess-i-do-not-like-losing-neither-always-winning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Physics badminton is expanding. Originally I have got together four
people and played on a weekly basis. Now we have 8 people playing on two
courts and 2 to 3 times a week. It is not the first time I realize I do
not like losing. My nerve naturally gets tightened when I am on a losing
track and I can not even squeeze a smile out of my face. People must
have believed I am far too serious. It is not a pleasant feeling but the
thing I am concerned most is that it may not be pleasant for others. On
the other hand, when Aya and me played as the Asian team, we always won
over the European team: Michele and Ben. I definitely lost interest
after a little while because it was not enough challenge. The right
altitude I believe should be: Feel rejoiced when winning; control better
when losing. Afterall, no failure, no progress! Just like No pain, No
gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not wish to be a bad loser!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Things I will have to do!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/things-i-will-have-to-do.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-16T17:18:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-16:things-i-will-have-to-do.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New era, new plans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many things I always wanted to do and did not manage to do
them well, such as tennis, guitar, Spanish, Dutch and Swimming. I will
have to learn Dutch well since I will be living there since October. I
will have to learn swimming well since I was nearly drowned in the sea.
I will have to learn guitar well, since I always wish to impress Ralf
with my music. Spanish, since I always wish to travel around the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Hello, people!</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-07-14T10:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2007-07-14:hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, Jing's Corner is a symbol of beginning of new era of my life. This
summer is fruitful, which is the special reason to set up this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf's job offer from MIT was a good start of this new era. After this
event, things move quite rapidly for him. Tomorrow (17/07/2007), he is
going to be a real Doctor of Philosophy in physics even though he feels
like a doctor long ago. I admire him for his confidence. He submitted a
hard copy of his thesis to the Senate house because he believed that was
it and he was not expecting any changes to his thesis by his examiners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, things are moving forward definitely even though it was not as
fast. But i have nothing to complain about. I got my first job offer
ever in my life on July 11th, which was a date mixed with excitement and
confusion. I am going to be an engineer working for ASML, which is the
world leading lithography company. This means I can proudly mark myself
as a young professional in semiconductor industry. Fine, that sounds
great but how about the next two years or &amp;gt; two years apart from my
love. I am not worried about myself but Ralf because I will have enough
time to take care of myself. Ralf is the person who has to work at least
50 hours per week! &lt;strong&gt;To Ralf, please do not indulge yourself with
America burgers or microwave food!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we will adapt ourself to the distance. (Chinese) People
say that 距离产生美 (Distance makes perfect) . Sure, no doubt everything
has its beautiful side. I will be staying at our home in Eindhoven, and
Ralf will be on a long-term business&amp;nbsp; trip in Boston. Time will fly by
and the proof will find its way in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>