<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jing's Corner</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/</id><updated>2013-11-13T23:37:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Reading list</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/Reading%20list.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-13T23:37:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-11-13:Reading list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;During my holiday in Algarve, I have finished 3 books:
Country driving: a Chinese road trip by Peter Hessler;
The kite runner by Khaled Hosseini;
The little coffee shop in Kabul by Debbie Rodriguez;
I enjoyed all of them very much. The book over China is more of a diary, recording
what Peter Hessler has experienced during his stay in China. I chose this book intentional
just to see China from a foreigner's point of view. Though there are not a lot of surprises
for me in the book, I am really amazed by the close contact he had with the local people.
He was really involved in their lives and befriended them and shared partially their life.
The other two books are fictions set in Kabul with the background of Russian invasion
and Taliban control. Great story line and very easy read. I had to cry several times while
reading the kite runner since I was really touched by the loyalty and friendship of Hassan
to Amir. After finishing the book, I watched the movie again. The movie is a lot less
touching since it simply missed too many details. But guess that is always the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will make a reading list of books of different countries. It can be real
stories or fictions as long as it does truly reflect the real history and culture of its
time.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>From Wordpress to Github</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/From%20Wordpress%20to%20Github.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-19T21:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2013-10-19:From Wordpress to Github.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As it says in the title, today is the grand opening of my new website. All the posts from
Wordpress which I wrote in the past have been moved. From now to the end of this year, I
will continue improving the site. So if you have any suggestion, please let me know. At
the moment, there are still some bugs. Hopefully they will get fixed after I learn better
how Pelican, css and html work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this new site, I hope that I can write more frequently. I know I have said the same
thing many times before, but hopefully this time, it will become true.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Caption of album items</title><link href="http://jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner/caption-of-album-items.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-21T12:08:00+01:00</updated><author><name>zouzoujing</name></author><id>tag:jingjingzou.github.io/jingscorner,2008-12-21:caption-of-album-items.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have added some captions to the photos in my photo album. Some stories
are told that way. So please do not miss out :) I remember Olga once
asked about it, so in the future I will try my best to release the
photos with captions. Then I will definately select my photos more
carefully to upload each time, since after one weekend trip, definately
more than 400 photos. Well, it is free afterall;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>